<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Complaining &#8211; MarvWeb</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/complaining/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 21:03:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Loss of Customer Service to the Rise of Automation</title>
		<link>/the-loss-of-customer-service-to-the-rise-of-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 21:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Complaining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you have an issue with the current state of Customer Service, please press 1. The trend of automation at the expense of value needs to end. I had some terrible experiences with &#8220;Customer Service&#8221; phone lines today that made me reflect on how often this has been happening recently. It&#8217;s incredibly frustrating to call [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>If you have an issue with the current state of Customer Service, please press 1. The trend of automation at the expense of value needs to end.</em></p>



<p>I had some terrible experiences with &#8220;Customer Service&#8221; phone lines today that made me reflect on how often this has been happening recently. It&#8217;s incredibly frustrating to call a company with a problem only to be confronted by an automated system that needs to be defeated to reach someone who can actually help.</p>



<p>When was the last time you called a business and a person picked up with no automated system in between? When was the last time an automated system was able to answer a question that you had that you weren&#8217;t already able to Google the solution to? </p>



<p>Automated phone systems have risen to the point where nearly every business you call will immediately relegate your call to one first in an attempt to not have to actually deal with you. While AI could some day replace the role of Customer Service Representatives, that day is not now.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Minimal Costs, Maximum Marketing, No Value to Customers</h2>



<p>With the interconnectivity of the world growing rapidly, Customer Service is often outsourced to extremely cheap call centers. This can often lead to costs for Customer Service agents being less than the US minimum wage. Even with less than minimum wage employees, companies still choose to not hire enough to avoid multi-hour wait times for customers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8987" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>On top of minimal costs, wait times are not just music anymore. Advertising and marketing now constantly berate you while you are waiting for help. There is actually an incentive for companies to have multi-hour wait times because it means you will be listening to hours of marketing. Since you are already involved with the company in some way, this marketing ends up being the even more effective &#8220;targeted&#8221; type of marketing. And of course, in between the marketing they will remind you how you can use their other automated system online in an attempt to avoid having to talk to you.</p>



<p>Despite minimal costs and free targeted marketing, these call centers often can&#8217;t even help you. Most of the time they will end up referring you to some online form to go through some automated system or tell you that someone who can actually help you will call you back in the next few days. Their inability to help would be easier to deal with if it didn&#8217;t come with all the marketing and wasted time. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">24/7 Automated Customer Service</h2>



<p>Have you noticed how most of these Customer Service lines tout themselves as being 24/7 service? Like it&#8217;s some big accomplishment that you can call an automated line any time of the day. If a 24/7 automated service can&#8217;t help, it may as well be closed; a closed call center is just as helpful. It&#8217;s so disingenuous to call these automated systems &#8220;24/7 Customer Service,&#8221; but with the prevalence of unsubstantiated claims in marketing, it isn&#8217;t much of a surprise.  </p>



<p>As a computer savvy person, when I call a Customer Service line the chances are I&#8217;ve already exhausted every automated online solution in an attempt to not have to talk with someone. And yet, the first thing I have to do to reach a person who can properly parse my issue is go through the spoken version of what I just did online.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="402" src="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-tree.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8990" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-tree.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-tree-300x241.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<p>I remember not too long ago that you could just spam &#8220;0&#8221; until the automated system gave up and put you through to someone. I haven&#8217;t found that to be true anymore with modern systems. Now they will just repeat the automated tree choices or sometimes even just hang up on you. On top of that, if you go down the wrong path of the automated tree, sometimes you&#8217;ll end up with a fully automated response with no chance of talking to someone. It&#8217;s actually becoming a skill to be able to reach a real Customer Service rep. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Future of Customer Service</h2>



<p>I don&#8217;t see this getting any better any time soon. Similar to the rise of self-checkouts at grocery stores, society is becoming increasingly accepting of terrible automated systems as the norm. I&#8217;d love to change to a company that doesn&#8217;t employ these automated systems but it is getting harder and harder to find them. If every company in a field is doing something you object to, your only viable option is to not engage with that field at all anymore, which isn&#8217;t really much of an option for many things. </p>



<p>What is there left to do? What power do customers have when every company that exists is doing it? Do I need to start my own bank to avoid having to sit on hold with my bank for hours every time I need help? Do I not use banks? Do I petition the government to intervene? Do I write a blog post complaining about it all?</p>



<p>Because we are forced to deal with it, it becomes normalized. As it becomes normalized, companies push it even further. As companies pushes it further, we are forced to deal with it. They are constantly towing the line where customers will complain about it, but won&#8217;t do anything about it. </p>



<p>We&#8217;re moving quicker every year toward more and more extreme anti-customer practices. Every good business person knows that good Customer Service leads to a more successful business, but the bar for &#8220;good&#8221; is in a constant, sharp decline. </p>



<p>How long before we&#8217;re so tired of the newest cost cutting Customer Service system that we&#8217;re relieved to hear a friendly automated voice ask us to press 1?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
