<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MarvWeb</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 21:09:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Theory: Pluto is the Master of Masters</title>
		<link>/pluto-is-the-master-of-masters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 18:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=2142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are too many oddities surrounding Pluto for them to be merely coincidence. There are too many scenes where Pluto is acting out of the norm for him to just be Mickey's loyal pet.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>SPOILERS AHEAD &#8211; I WILL BE PULLING FACTS FROM MANY KINGDOM HEARTS GAMES</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>ONLY READ ON IF YOU ARE CAUGHT UP WITH THE STORY UP UNTIL THE END OF KH3</em></p>



<p>With the announcement of Kingdom Hearts IV, I wanted to put one of my Kingdom Hearts theories out there. In this post I&#8217;ll share with you all the hints that have been there all along that lead me to this conclusion. If it ends up being true, I can say that I called it and point to this post as proof!</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the theory: <strong>the Master of Masters has disguised himself as King Mickey&#8217;s dog Pluto</strong>.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who is the Master of Masters (MoM)</h2>



<p>There is a lot of extra lore for the Kingdom Hearts universe, so I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised to hear that you don&#8217;t even know who the Master of Masters is. The MoM has really only been explored in the mobile game Kingdom Hearts <em>χ</em> (Chi, like the Chi blade from KH3). He is the first known Keyblade Master, with no known master that taught him. He trained some of the first Keyblade Masters we know of in history who went on to train other Masters, making him the Master of Masters.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX.webp"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="300" height="731" src="/wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-9401" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX-123x300.webp 123w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The MoM as he appeared in KHχ</figcaption></figure>



<p>He claims that he can see into the future using his Gazing Eye, which he uses to make predictions or possibly see how his choices play out. The eye is part of a Keyblade that the MoM passes down to his apprentice. The Keyblade is said to have no name by the MoM, but considering it contains the Gazing Eye, many know it now as the Gazing Eye Keyblade. This is the Keyblade we see old Xehanort wield.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort.png"><img decoding="async" width="653" height="490" src="/wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9344" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort.png 653w, /wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort-300x225.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 653px) 100vw, 653px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Xehanort wielding the Gazing Eye Keyblade</figcaption></figure>



<p>The MoM decided to pass some of this knowledge of the future on to five Keyblade masters he dubbed the Foretellers, telling each to build a group of Keyblade wielders and tasking each group with specific goals. He gave each of them a Book of Prophecies to help them with their goal, presumably written using the insight he gained from the Gazing Eye. However, he created one of these books for each of them and told them not to share the contents with anyone, even their fellow Foretellers. It&#8217;s likely that each book was different, and specifically written to influence events as he had planned or foresaw.</p>



<p>As shown in Kingdom Hearts χ Back Cover (worth a watch if you haven&#8217;t seen it), the MoM has foreseen the Keyblade war and predicts that &#8220;Darkness will prevail and the light will expire.&#8221; He believes the war to be inevitable, so his main goal is to take care of what happens afterwards, implying that he wants to shape events so that they happen the way he wants them to.</p>



<p>Prior to tasking the Foretellers with their roles, the MoM handed one other task to his apprentice Luxu. He gave Luxu the Gazing Eye Keyblade to watch everything that was going to transpire from afar. He told Luxu to train an apprentice of his own and bequeath him the Gazing Eye Keyblade. This would presumably allow him to view the events of the future, and help him craft his Book(s) of Prophecy just right as to shape the outcome. He also gave Luxu a large black box, of which the contents are currently unknown, that he was to keep safe. As of KH3, Maleficent seems to be trying to find this box for unknown reasons.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum.png"><img decoding="async" width="751" height="557" src="/wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9084" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum.png 751w, /wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum-300x223.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 751px) 100vw, 751px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Gazing Eye Keyblade hanging in Scala Ad Caelum</figcaption></figure>



<p>How does this all tie in to the mainline Kingdom Hearts games? Well now that the Dark Seeker (Xehanort) saga is complete, the next saga has been dubbed the &#8220;Lost Masters&#8221; saga, almost certainly referencing the Master of Master&#8217;s storyline. This prediction is almost fully confirmed by one of the ending scenes of KH3 that sees Xigbar, wielding the Gazing Eye Keyblade and standing over the black box, summon back four of the five Foretellers and reveal himself to be Luxu. He announces that the role the MoM gave him is finally complete.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="586" src="/wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-1024x586.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8207" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-1024x586.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-300x172.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-768x440.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-1536x879.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu.jpg 1682w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Xigbar reveals himself to be Luxu</figcaption></figure>



<p>There&#8217;s a lot of lore I&#8217;m skipping over here that involves the MoM, but that should be sufficient for the purposes of this theory. On to Pluto!</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Every Scene with Pluto in the Kingdom Hearts Series</h2>



<p>I found a video by the YouTube channel OzBroGamerz that contains every scene I&#8217;m about to talk about . You can check it out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zEOGzqq12aU&amp;ab_channel=OzBroGamerz">here</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts &#8211; King Mickey Goes Missing</h3>



<p>The first scene we see Pluto in has him waiting patiently behind King Mickey&#8217;s throne for someone to discover that Mickey has run off. He is holding a letter presumably written by Mickey that informs Donald that Mickey has gone off to investigate why the stars have been going out. While the letter is being shown to us on screen, we see Pluto sleeping peacefully in his bed. The contents of the letter are as follows:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Donald,<br>Sorry to rush off without sayin&#8217; goodbye, but there&#8217;s big trouble brewin&#8217;.<br>Not sure why, but the stars have been blinkin&#8217; out, one by one. And that means disaster can&#8217;t be far behind. I hate to leave you all but I&#8217;ve gotta go check into it.<br>There&#8217;s someone with a &#8220;Key&#8221;—the Key to our survival. So I need you and Goofy to find him, and stick with him. Got it?<br>We need that key or we&#8217;re doomed! So go to Traverse Town and find Leon. He&#8217;ll point you in the right direction.<br>P.S. Would ya apologize to Minnie for me? Thanks, pal.<br>Signed &#8211; Mickey</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="689" height="449" src="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9294" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1.png 689w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1-300x196.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 689px) 100vw, 689px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto is shown while the letter is read</figcaption></figure>



<p>Take a second and reread the letter, but pretend it is instead the MoM that has written it, not Mickey. This letter makes so much more sense if it was written by someone who could see into the future. It is vague on details, but very specific on instructions. </p>



<p>First off, why is this letter addressed specifically to Donald? Why not Goofy? How did Mickey know that Pluto would deliver this letter specifically to Donald? Also, why is it written this way? Look at Mickey&#8217;s letter written at the end of Re: Coded. His letter (that we see him writing) uses much more formal language. You could argue that Mickey wrote this letter much more whimsically because it was addressed to Donald. However, would Mickey rush off and leave his home in such a hurry for something that was just &#8220;big trouble brewin&#8217;.&#8221; To me, this letter sound more like someone pretending to be Mickey by mirroring his speech, but not his writing style.</p>



<p>Second, why not tell Donald in person? It&#8217;s not like this matter of noticing &#8220;stars blinking out&#8221; was so pressing that he couldn&#8217;t talk to his friends first. Was Mickey concerned that Donald would try to stop him? As the King, I think he can do as he pleases. Was he concerned that Donald and Goofy would want to come with him? If he was concerned for their safety, why would he send them to find the Keyblade? </p>



<p>At the end of this opening scene, we see Pluto leap into the Gummy Ship, joining Donald and Goofy on their adventure.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pluto in Traverse Town</h3>



<p>We see Pluto walking with Donald and Goofy in the opening, but Pluto quickly wanders off from the group, stumbling upon Sora passed out. He licks him awake, and then forcefully hits Sora to snap him out of his daze. When Sora asks Pluto if he knows where they are, Pluto excitedly runs off leading Sora to Leon and the others. After this, we don&#8217;t see Pluto until the very end of the first game.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="695" height="551" src="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9292" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora.png 695w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora-300x238.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 695px) 100vw, 695px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto hitting Sora</figcaption></figure>



<p>This scene is described in later games as the start of Sora&#8217;s journey. And who was there to get him started? Pluto. Pluto licking Sora is uninteresting enough, but aggressively hitting him with his paws shortly after because Sora believes himself to still be dreaming? Really, <a href="https://youtu.be/zEOGzqq12aU?t=451">watch the scene yourself,</a> it&#8217;s oddly aggressive and intentional for a dog. Once Sora is up and about and asking questions, Pluto runs off. His role complete, we don&#8217;t see Pluto again until the end of the game. Where does he go?</p>



<p>When Sora, Donald, and Goofy eventually run into Leon, Yuffie, and Aerith, they don&#8217;t seem to know exactly what is going on either, despite the recommendation from &#8220;Mickey.&#8221; They know that Heartless are attracted to the Keyblade and not much else. It sounds like they got a similar vague letter that was light on details and heavy on instruction.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts Ending</h3>



<p>At the end of Kingdom Hearts 1, we see Pluto one last time. Sora, Donald, and Goofy are walking through a field discussing what they should do next. As the three of them realize they don&#8217;t have much to go on, Pluto saunters across their path holding a letter with the King&#8217;s seal in his mouth. Rather than give them the letter, Pluto runs off, getting the crew to chase him. The camera pulls away, and the game ends with the final, non voice acted line &#8220;Remember Sora, you are the one who will open the door to the light.&#8221; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="855" height="471" src="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9298" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter.png 855w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter-300x165.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter-768x423.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 855px) 100vw, 855px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">What a coincidence</figcaption></figure>



<p>This is the first scene that really made me question Pluto. You may write this off as the devs having a bit of fun, hinting nonspecifically at more adventures to come in a game they weren&#8217;t certain they&#8217;d continue, but this is too odd when taken as explicit canon. Why would Pluto not give them the letter? How did he happen to show up EXACTLY when the crew was without purpose?</p>



<p>This field is not in Traverse Town (at least as far as I can tell), so Pluto somehow got to a different world. Lore wise we know that this should only be possible using Corridors of Darkness or a ship like the Gummi Ship. So how would Pluto have made it to another world? When did he meet up with Mickey to get this letter? Scene from KH2 and Coded show other times Pluto has used Corridors of Darkness. </p>



<p>The final quote is similar to the other detached non voice acted lines we hear throughout the game. It seems <a href="https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/boards/943347-kingdom-hearts-birth-by-sleep/57971099">Nomura has confirmed</a> that the voice we hear in the beginning is actually Mickey, but he is very specific by saying Mickey is speaking to Sora&#8217;s heart when he acquires the Keyblade and just before passing through the last door of the End of the World. So who is speaking here? It would make sense for the MoM to know that Sora was destined to open the Door of Light in KH2.</p>



<p>Finally, if you look at Pluto after the team start running after him, he doesn&#8217;t even have the letter in his mouth anymore. An oversight by the devs? Perhaps. Or perhaps the letter was just a fake made to get Sora and the others to chase him toward the next place he needed them to be.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts: Chain of Memories &#8211; Castle Oblivion</h3>



<p>Chain of Memories opens right where KH1 left off, showing the second half of the final scene with the team running after Pluto. We see that the team has given up the chase of Pluto, and are sleeping for the night. Someone in a signature Black Cloak (very likely Marluxia) appears to Sora and tells him that &#8220;Ahead lies something you need.&#8221; Sora then finds himself outside of Castle Oblivion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="590" src="/wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-1024x590.png" alt="" class="wp-image-8966" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-1024x590.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-300x173.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-768x442.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion.png 1106w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto led them straight to Marluxia</figcaption></figure>



<p>Perhaps you could say that Marluxia could have abducted Sora from anywhere and taken him to Castle Oblivion; perhaps the spot Pluto led them to was irrelevant for Marluxia&#8217;s plot. But once again, it&#8217;s all too odd to be overlooked. We see Pluto give the letter to Donald at the start of KH1, but this time he runs away from the team, refusing to give them the letter. Pluto even manages to lose them completely, right before Marluxia shows up and CoM starts.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fighting Alone Isn&#8217;t Easy</h3>



<p>As Sora makes his way through Castle Oblivion, he comes to the conclusion that &#8220;fighting alone isn&#8217;t as easy as [he] thought.&#8221; Two cards (Sora&#8217;s memories) float down behind him and manifest into Donald and Goofy in a big display of light and sound. After a quick conversation, the three discover that Pluto is sitting silently behind Sora. Donald questions what he&#8217;s doing here, but Goofy reassures him it makes sense since they all came to Traverse Town together. Jiminy consults the journal and reminds everyone that Pluto left Donald and Goofy before they met up with Sora. We don&#8217;t see Pluto any more in CoM.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="852" height="573" src="/wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9460" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here.png 852w, /wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here-300x202.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here-768x517.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 852px) 100vw, 852px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Good question Donald, what IS Pluto doing here?</figcaption></figure>



<p>Ok, the lore for Chain of Memories was tough, but my understanding is that everything inside Castle Oblivion was Sora&#8217;s memories. This scene explicitly shows Sora creating memories of Donald and Goofy to help him, manifesting them from cards. So then why was Pluto here with them? If Sora had JUST gotten to the memories of his best friends, why would he have already manifested Pluto? We didn&#8217;t see or hear Pluto appear, so he must have already been around. The crew are even explicitly confused as to why Pluto is here, but get distracted by the rest of the odd happenings and don&#8217;t speak any more about it.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s more likely that this Pluto is actually not a memory, but the real Pluto who has also entered Castle Oblivion to watch and monitor what transpires. Everything goes to plan, so the MoM doesn&#8217;t have to interfere further in this game.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts II &#8211; Pluto and the Corridor of Darkness</h3>



<p>We see Pluto in The World That Never Was chasing after Axel as he walks through a Corridor of Darkness. The Corridor closes behind him and Pluto is sad he missed it. He is happy though to discover that another Corridor has opened just behind him and quickly runs through. (In the original version of this scene, someone whistles to him, but not in Final Mix.)</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="606" height="802" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9291" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness.jpg 606w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness-227x300.jpg 227w" sizes="(max-width: 606px) 100vw, 606px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto delves into the darkness</figcaption></figure>



<p>Ok, if you haven&#8217;t agreed with any of my points so far, you have to at least admit this is a weird scene. First off, why is Pluto in The World That Never Was, the home base of Organization XIII. How is he surviving in a world full of Heartless and Nobodies? How can Pluto survive the corridors when everyone else that uses them has to wear a protective cloak?</p>



<p>The scenes that follow hint that Riku is opening these portals for Pluto. However, this is not the only time Pluto enters corridors. Are multiple members of Organization XIII using Pluto? In truth, we don&#8217;t know who is teleporting Pluto around or why.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pluto to the Rescue</h3>



<p>Axel arrives to capture Kairi. Before she can agree to go with him, Pluto arrives and seems to warn her of Axel. A whistle is heard and another Corridor of Darkness appears. Pluto aggressively encourages Kairi to go through the corridor with him. They appear in some place with floating Nobody symbols all around before another whistle spawns a corridor before them. This corridor however is not dark like we&#8217;ve come to know, but light. Kairi sees a masked figure before the corridor closes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1003" height="947" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9295" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi.jpg 1003w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi-300x283.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi-768x725.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A corridor of light?</figcaption></figure>



<p>I think this is the only corridor we see that looks like this. The only other thing I can think of that resembles this is the Door to Light that Sora and Riku use to escape the Realm of Darkness.  But perhaps it&#8217;s just that every Corridor of Darkness takes them to this transit hub, but from this side, connecting back to a world looks like a Corridor of Light.</p>



<p>Talking about Pluto specifically though, even if you believe that all of these portal were just Riku&#8217;s plan, Pluto seems to know exactly what to do. No fear or hesitation, it&#8217;s almost like he knows what should be happening and is happy to keep things on track.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pluto and Kairi Captured</h3>



<p>Once Sora catches up with Roxas&#8217;s friends in Twilight Town, they tell him about how Kairi stayed with them for a while. In the flashback, we see Pluto is there too. Axel finds them and takes Kairi. Pluto follows them through the corridor. </p>



<p>In the next scene we see that Pluto and Kairi are locked up in the Castle That Never Was. Pluto comforts Kairi until Namine appears in another Corridor of Darkness, telling Kairi to come with her. Saix appear to block their path, but is soon driven off by Riku. As Saix is escaping, Riku plans to follow him. Kairi calls out for him to wait, but he doesn&#8217;t turn away from the corridor until Pluto runs up to him barking, getting between him and the portal. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="832" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-1024x832.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9297" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-1024x832.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-300x244.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-768x624.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku.jpg 1104w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto convinces Riku when Kairi could not</figcaption></figure>



<p>Many took this scene as Pluto happy to see Riku since he&#8217;s been helping him through this Kairi plot, but if you watch the scene, Pluto clearly tries to stop Riku from pursuing Saix. This gives Riku a chance to talk with Kairi, potentially putting him back of the path to redemption he is destined for.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Re: Coded Retcon</h3>



<p>Re: Coded gives us one new scene involving Pluto. During the all-hands-in forming of the Sora-Donald-Goofy alliance, we see Pluto in the distance sniffing the ground. A corridor of Darkness appears before him and Pluto runs through. Back in Mickey&#8217;s Castle, real Donald asks why that showed up at all, and Jiminy comments that he certainly didn&#8217;t write that.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="552" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-1024x552.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9296" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-1024x552.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-300x162.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-768x414.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off.png 1201w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto sneaks off</figcaption></figure>



<p>Perhaps it is just the devs adding a scene to answer the question as to how Pluto got around in the first few games. However, even if you take that as true, who opened the corridor for Pluto this time? It wouldn&#8217;t have been Riku yet. And again, how is Pluto able to use these corridors so often with no protection?</p>



<p>Similar to Chain of Memories, my understanding of Coded is a bit weak. I believe that the journal that Mickey uses is just the one that Jiminy wrote, which happened to include some extra stuff Jiminy did not write. The insights gained from exploring the journal are used to help put Sora on his path in saving everyone in KH3. So who added this specific data about Pluto to the journal and why? Jiminy specifically calls out that he didn&#8217;t write this. While the other games have been rather covert with their Pluto hints, this game wants you to notice Pluto and the oddity surrounding him.</p>



<p>It seems most people believe the person who added to the journal was Namine, or data-Namine. But Malificent specificaly comments about he Book of Prophecies in Coded, even hinting that Jiminy&#8217;s journal may be somehow tied to it. She says that the Book of Prophecies can create worlds, much like the Datascape and the plot of Coded. Also, the rhyming scheme of this quote added to Jiminy&#8217;s journal reminds me of the two quotes from the Book of Prophecies we have heard:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Their hurting will be mended when you return to end it.</p>
<cite><strong>Page added to Jiminy&#8217;s Journal</strong></cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>On that fated land, a great war shall transpire. Darkness will prevail and the light expire.</p>
<cite><strong>Book of Prophecies Final Entry</strong></cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>Imbalance observed, strength misplaced, a future filled with sorrow.</em></p>



<p><em>Words of truth misunderstood as they explore the secret of tomorrow.</em></p>



<p><em>With a single strike, toll the bells and herald the end, bringing war upon us, as fate did intend.</em></p>
<cite><strong>Book of Prophecies Lost Page</strong></cite></blockquote>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"> Putting It All Together</h3>



<p>There are too many oddities surrounding Pluto for them to be merely coincidence. There are too many scenes where Pluto is acting out of the norm for him to just be Mickey&#8217;s loyal pet. And is it not fitting too that the MoM would turn himself into a dog? From the little we know of the MoM&#8217;s personality, playing a dog would be a perfect role for him. </p>



<p>I can easily imagine him telling us during the reveal that he&#8217;s been there the whole time, making sure everyone stayed on track. Flashbacks to many of these scenes will play to show the player all the hints that were there. Everyone will be shocked and surprised, but not us!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto.webp"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="232" height="299" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-9290"/></a></figure>



<p>The Master of Masters has been with us since the beginning, hiding his identity. <strong>Pluto is the Master of Masters.</strong></p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warframe Prime Resurgence &#8211; How to Earn Aya</title>
		<link>/warframe-prime-resurgence-temporary-vaulted-prime-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 18:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warframe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prime Resurgence is an event in Warframe that will temporarily replace the existing Vaulted Relic system for Prime parts.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Prime Resurgence</h2>



<p>Prime Resurgence is an event in Warframe that will temporarily replace the existing Vaulted Relic system for Prime parts. Instead of earning the current &#8220;unvaulted&#8221; relics from missions in the void, Tenno will instead earn a new currency, Aya, that can be spent on vaulted relics. The relics available to be purchased will change each week of the event.</p>



<p>You will also be able to purchase a premium version of Aya, Regal Aya, for real money. This premium currency can be spent to purchase the Prime weapons and warframes outright instead of going through the normal relic process. It can also be used to purchase items given out as part of the Amazon Prime &#8220;Prime Gaming&#8221; program. Regal Aya will not be earnable in game, cannot be purchased with Platinum, and cannot be traded; the only way to get Regal Aya is to buy it. </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">When is  Prime Resurgence </h2>



<p>Prime Resurgence will be available from <strong>November 16th, 2021</strong> until <strong>January 25th, 2022</strong>. Each week will feature a different pair of Prime Warframes and their associated Prime weapons. The schedule is as follows:</p>



<ul>
<li>Nov. 16 &#8211; Nov. 22: Mag &amp; Nova  </li>



<li>Nov. 23 &#8211; Nov. 29: Limbo &amp; Trinity</li>



<li>Nov. 30 &#8211; Dec. 06: Mesa &amp; Hydroid</li>



<li>Dec. 07 &#8211; Dec. 13: Volt &amp; Loki</li>



<li>Dec. 14 &#8211; Dec. 20: Vauban &amp; Ash</li>



<li>Dec. 21 &#8211; Dec. 27: Oberon &amp; Nekros</li>



<li>Dec. 28 &#8211; Jan. 03: Valkyr &amp; Saryn</li>



<li>Jan. 04 &#8211; Jan. 10: Ember &amp; Frost</li>



<li>Jan 11. &#8211; Jan. 18: Mag, Nova, Limbo, Trinity, Hydroid, Mesa, Volt, &amp; Loki</li>



<li>Jan. 18 &#8211; Jan. 25: Ash, Vauban, Nekros, Oberon, Saryn, Valkyr, Ember, &amp; Frost</li>
</ul>



<p>The final two weeks of the event will be a last chance to participate in the event, likely offering multiple Primes that were offered in previous weeks.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Farm Aya</h2>



<p>Aya will replace &#8220;unvaulted&#8221; relics during the event, meaning that doing missions in the Void and Bounties on Cetus/Fortuna/Necralisk has a chance to earn you the new currency. The amount of Aya you earn is not dependent upon the era of the relic; you earn one Aya for every vaulted Axi, Neo, Meso, and Lith relic you would have otherwise gotten. Since you can buy the Axi relics for one Aya, this essentially means you can trade a vaulted Lith for a vaulted Axi &#8211; a good trade! </p>



<p>Spamming short Void missions like Hepit, Ukko, or Marduk is the most effective way of farming Aya, but there is some luck involved since you will only earn Aya if you would have normally gotten a vaulted relic. Since relic rarity doesn&#8217;t seem to matter, The Capture missions are the better choice. <strong>Hepit will be the fastest way to farm</strong>, with Ukko being only slightly behind it because of the increased enemy level. As with most Capture mission farms, if you mission changes to an Exterminate, it is often faster to leave and restart the mission.</p>



<p>Bounties are also a good way to earn Aya, but these missions will take much longer to complete. Choose to do bounties if you need reputation with the associated faction or other items that come from bounties. If you are just looking to maximize Aya, Void missions are better.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/void-missions.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="631" src="/wp-content/uploads/void-missions-1024x631.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9419" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/void-missions-1024x631.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/void-missions-300x185.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/void-missions-768x473.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/void-missions.png 1302w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Missions in the Void will drop Aya</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Spend Aya</h2>



<p>Aya can be spent at Varzia who is located in Maroo&#8217;s Bazaar on Mars during the event. In addition to the current offering of vaulted relics, you can also purchase Syandanas, Orbiter skins, Sigils, Glyphs, and Ducats.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Lore of Aya</h2>



<p>Varzia describes Aya as an &#8220;Orokin sequencing medium.&#8221; This means that Aya is a type of storage material used by the Orokin. The Orokin used Aya in Ayatan Statues to record many of their violent acts. Varzia is happy that Maroo is melting down these statues and erasing the terrible history of the Orokin. She believes that the Prime Warframe data held within should be retained though.</p>



<p>I couldn&#8217;t help but think of a particular Twitch emote when seeing the name though&#8230;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="300" height="300" src="/wp-content/uploads/ayaya-twitch-emote.png" alt="" class="wp-image-8949" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/ayaya-twitch-emote.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/ayaya-twitch-emote-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The AYAYA Emote on Twitch</figcaption></figure>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">External Links</h2>



<p>Be sure to check out the official page for <a href="https://www.warframe.com/prime-resurgence">Warframe&#8217;s Prime Resurgence</a>. </p>



<p>New War is coming to Warframe sometime in December 2021! Check out the official page for the <a href="https://www.warframe.com/news/the-new-war-launches-in-december">New War announcement</a>.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Golden Kappa is Not Random &#8211; It is Handed Out By Specific Users</title>
		<link>/golden-kappa-is-not-random-it-is-handed-out-by-specific-users/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The code snippet shown here implies that a list of specific users are able to assign the Golden Kappa to anyone they want. It may be that there is another part of the code that assigns it randomly, but even if that is true, these users can assign additional Golden Kappas at their own discretion. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LivestreamFail/comments/q2gooi/twitchtv_got_leaked_like_the_entire_website/hfl3tyu/?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3">recent leak of popular streaming site Twitch.tv</a> has put the entire source code of how the site works out on the internet for everyone to see, comments and all. One of the first things that peaked people&#8217;s attention was to finally see behind the curtain of how Twitch assigns the elusive &#8220;Golden Kappa.&#8221; Per the source code, it seems that Golden Kappa is not as random as people believed.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is the Golden Kappa</h2>



<p>For those not in-the-know, &#8220;Golden Kappa&#8221; refers to a Golden version of a well known emote on Twitch. The normal emote, Kappa, is one of the most well-known emotes on the site. It is often used to convey a sense of sarcasm, much like &#8220;/s&#8221; is used on other social sites. The basic Kappa emote is a greyscale picture of Josh DeSeno, a programmer for Justin.tv, the early version of Twitch. As the name implies, &#8220;Golden Kappa&#8221; is the same picture with a golden look rather than the greyscale. The golden version is also only two colors, making it flatter and appear a bit more as an award of sorts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="356" height="253" src="/wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9089" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa.jpg 356w, /wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa-300x213.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 356px) 100vw, 356px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Kappa (left) vs Golden Kappa (right)</figcaption></figure>



<p>While every user can use the global emote Kappa anywhere on Twitch, only a select few could use the golden version, and only for a short time. Prior to the leak, it was generally believed that every day, a select few users were randomly chosen as the Golden Kappas for the day. When these select users typed the Kappa emote into a chat, it would produce the golden version instead of the standard greyscale. </p>



<p>There was no notification or any indication that a user had been awarded access to the Golden Kappa. The only way to know that you were chosen was to type Kappa into chat. This led many to often do &#8220;Golden Kappa Checks,&#8221; where viewers of a stream would all spam the Kappa emote to see if any of them had been lucky enough to win the roll for that day.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Does the Golden Kappa Actually Work</h2>



<p>The code snippet shown here implies that a list of specific users are able to assign the Golden Kappa to anyone they want. It may be that there is another part of the code that assigns it randomly, but even if that is true, these users can assign additional Golden Kappas at their own discretion. As was speculated, the duration for how long a user is awarded the Golden Kappa is 24 hours.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa-code-snippetJPG.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="420" height="456" src="/wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa-code-snippetJPG.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9091" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa-code-snippetJPG.jpg 420w, /wp-content/uploads/golden-kappa-code-snippetJPG-276x300.jpg 276w" sizes="(max-width: 420px) 100vw, 420px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Code Snippet From &#8220;goldenkappa.go&#8221;</figcaption></figure>



<p>The leak has demystified a niche but exciting aspect of Twitch. What was once believed to be a free lottery that every user was entered into daily has instead been shown to simply be an award a select few users can hand out to whoever they like. While it still could be true that the Golden Kappa is relatively random, knowing that it is decided by bias prone humans instead of dispassionate code makes it a lot less exciting.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cooldown-Based Warframes &#8211; The Lavos Experiment</title>
		<link>/cooldown-based-warframes-the-lavos-experiment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Warframe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If Lavos's new cooldown-based system is going to continue for future Warframes, some changes need to be made.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The newest Warframe added in Operation: Orphix Venom, Lavos, is a truly unique Warframe. Lavos&#8217;s abilities use a traditional cooldown (CD) system rather the energy system every other Warframe uses (even Hildryn, to an extent). This is a new path for Warframe, and definitely one that I&#8217;m interested in future Warframes exploring more. However, if this cooldown system is going to continue some changes to the system need to be made.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tl-dr">TL;DR</h2>



<ul><li>Lavos&#8217;s ability&#8217;s CDs are too short, potentially leading to 100% of playtime</li><li>Short CDs discourage the use of weapons, an integral part of Warframe</li><li>CD based rotations don&#8217;t fit well into Warframe&#8217;s current playstyle as they encourage rotations rather pooling energy for the right situation</li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-role-of-warframe-abilities">The Role of Warframe Abilities</h2>



<p>This CD system has made me reevaluate what exactly I want from Warframe abilities. When I think of my personal favorite Warframes like Saryn and Nekros their abilities generally augment the core system of blade and gun. Even when their abilities don&#8217;t really interact with the core weapon based experience of Warframe, you&#8217;ll often quickly find yourself going right back into shooting and swinging.</p>



<p>The exception to this would be builds like Khora&#8217;s Whipclaw Crit build, where almost all of your damage ends up coming from the ability rather than weapons. Same with Volt Discharge in Sanctuary Onslaught; you end up just spamming the one ability rather than ever pulling out your weapon. The difference here though is that these Warframes still work as intended without these builds. Khora and Volt are perfectly effective with non ability-spam builds. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-much-time-is-left-in-between-lavos-s-abilities">How Much Time is Left In-Between Lavos&#8217;s Abilities</h2>



<p>Where I think the biggest issue lies with Lavos is that his cooldowns are so short that they encourage constant use. His abilities can be cast every <em>8/5/10/30 </em>seconds respectively. Disregarding the CD reduction from Transmutation Probe, in any 30 second window Lavos can spend up to 22.29 seconds casting abilities. That&#8217;s just under 75% of his time casting abilities. To further add to this time, each ability can also be augmented with a single (ex. Toxin) or dual (ex. Viral) element. Augmenting a single element takes about one second, so a dual Augment (arguably what you &#8220;should&#8221; be doing) would add two seconds to every cast. As you can see from the table below, <strong>you can choose to focus 100% of your time on casting Lavos&#8217;s abilities.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><thead><tr><th>Ability</th><th>Cooldown (sec)</th><th><strong>Cast Time* (sec)</strong></th><th>Time Between Uses** (sec)</th><th class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left">Max Casts / 30sec</th><th>Total Cast Time / 30sec*</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>(1) Ophidian Bite</td><td>8.00</td><td>1.50</td><td>9.50</td><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left">3.16</td><td>4.74</td></tr><tr><td>(2) Vial Rush</td><td>5.00</td><td>3.00</td><td>8.00</td><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left">3.75</td><td>11.25</td></tr><tr><td>(3) Transmutation Probe</td><td>10.00</td><td>2.00</td><td>15.00</td><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left">2.00</td><td>4.00</td></tr><tr><td>(4) Catalyze</td><td>30.00</td><td>2.50</td><td>32.50</td><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left">0.92</td><td>2.3</td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left"><strong>TOTAL</strong></td><td>22.29</td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left"><strong>Dual Element</strong> <strong>Augmented</strong></td><td>22.29 + 2(9.83) = 41.95</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption>* Cast Times are an estimate from my own testing, unmodded<br>** CD starts after cast and/or ability duration</figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-big-issue-mixing-weapons-into-lavos-s-playstyle">The Big Issue &#8211; Mixing Weapons Into Lavos&#8217;s Playstyle</h2>



<p>The above information shows that it is possible to ONLY cast abilities with Lavos, leaving zero time for weapon usage. The obvious argument is to just leave some of these abilities off CD for a while and do some damage with weapons. While I agree that you can always choose to do so, we here at MarvWeb aim for efficient and optimal gameplay.</p>



<p>The truth is that one of these two styles will be more effective at any time. If your weapons are better at killing enemies than your abilities, you should never cast those abilities. Conversely, if you abilities are better at killing enemies, you should use them as much as possible. The latter is often true with most Warframes: it is often true that abilities surpass weapons in effectiveness, meaning they take higher priority for efficient gameplay. Again, think of Khora&#8217;s Whipclaw: because Whipclaw is stronger than weapons and you can constantly use Whipclaw, from a min/max perspective, weapons should never be used.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have a potato&#8217;d, max forma&#8217;d Lavos, so I can&#8217;t say for sure which abilities of his end up surpassing weapons. However, since I view Lavos as an experiment for future Warframes, there is a chance that all of a CD-based Warframe&#8217;s abilities &#8220;should&#8221; be cast as often as possible to maximize DPS. <strong>If Lavos&#8217;s abilities are good, they &#8220;should&#8221; be all you do; if they are not good, then you &#8220;should&#8221; never cast them.</strong></p>



<p>This binary relationship is something that needs to be addressed with Lavos and any future CD-based Warframe. <strong>Weapons are an integral part of Warframe and a Warframe&#8217;s intended playstyle should not discourage their use. </strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-smaller-issue-energy-pooling-vs-casting-on-cooldown">A Smaller Issue &#8211; Energy Pooling vs. Casting on Cooldown</h2>



<p>The idea of Cooldowns also poses another issue. Often time in Warframe you will save your abilities for the perfect moment where they will be most effective. The reason we have this flexibility is the ability to pool energy without a lose of theoretical DPS. The mod Flow that increases your energy pool is so widely used because often time the best way to use energy is to wait for a good time, rather than use your energy the second you get it. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cd-warframe-abilities.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1624"/></figure></div>



<p>CD-based abilities however cannot be pooled; you are losing potential DPS every moment they are off CD. This leads to a use-or-lose mentality that is not fun to play, and feels antithetical to what I&#8217;ve loved about Warframe over the past almost eight years. If you try to save for the perfect scenario, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ll have been able to cast the ability multiple times in-between, effectively losing that DPS. If you use the ability whenever it comes off CD, it might be on CD when the perfect situation arises. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-change-in-playstyle-putting-all-your-eggs-into-one-ability">A Change in Playstyle &#8211; Putting All Your Eggs Into One Ability</h2>



<p>Similar to the pooling issue, most Warframe&#8217;s can choose to cast their &#8220;best&#8221; ability over and over. You can choose to dump all of your energy into a single ability, essentially offsetting the relative ineffectiveness of your other abilities. You can cast Volt&#8217;s Discharge way more often if you choose to not cast his other abilities. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/volt-discharge-featured-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1354"/></figure>



<p>Lavos, and potentially any other CD-based Warframe, cannot choose to ignore their less effective abilities to increase the usage of their more effective abilities. For instance, you cannot cast Catalyze more often by choosing to never cast Vial Rush. Catalyze is on a 30 sec CD, and nothing can be done about that. </p>



<p>This leads to a <em>rotation</em>, a term often used in MMOs and RPGs. The most effective way to play a CD-based Warframe will often come down pressing abilities the moment they come off CD. The issue here is that it leads to players having to constantly look at the bottom right to monitor their CDs so that they can execute them at the optimal time. </p>



<p>Many RPGs offset this issue by presenting CDs visually in an easy to see manner, allowing you to focus on the gameplay and see that the CD is ready without moving you eyes away from the action. Warframe currently does not have a system like this. Playing Lavos I find myself constantly looking at the CDs to see what is ready.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-fix-these-issues">How to Fix These Issues</h2>



<p>The fix to the major issue of invalidating weapons is really quite simple. These abilities need to have longer CDs and shorter cast times. This nerf can be offset by buffing the ability&#8217;s effectiveness or duration. To address the constant casting on Lavos, Elemental Augments should not go away once selected. This alone will remove up to two seconds of casting from every ability. Just make a new chosen element overwrite the existing one, reset the elemental augment after a decent amount of time, or give us a new single button to clear the chosen element.</p>



<p>Another good change that can avoid this situation for future CD-based Warframe abilities is to make the ability augment weapon-play rather than be independent of it. Abilities should integrate into weapon gameplay, not replace it. Abilities could increase to weapon damage, add an elemental augment to weapons, add an AoE to weapons, etc. This would be great candidates for CD based abilities. Don&#8217;t give them constant uptime; let us activate them when we need the increased damage against groups or tough enemies. This temporary increase in power at the right moment is what is so rewarding about similar systems in MMOs and RPGs.</p>



<p>The issue with pooling vs. casting on CD can be offset with a simple charge system. Having multiple charges smooths CDs and allows you to essentially pool your CDs for the right moment. You don&#8217;t feel obligated to use an ability as soon as it&#8217;s ready because you are still actively gaining another charge, eliminating the potential lost DPS.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Loss of Customer Service to the Rise of Automation</title>
		<link>/the-loss-of-customer-service-to-the-rise-of-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 21:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Complaining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you have an issue with the current state of Customer Service, please press 1. The trend of automation at the expense of value needs to end. I had some terrible experiences with &#8220;Customer Service&#8221; phone lines today that made me reflect on how often this has been happening recently. It&#8217;s incredibly frustrating to call [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>If you have an issue with the current state of Customer Service, please press 1. The trend of automation at the expense of value needs to end.</em></p>



<p>I had some terrible experiences with &#8220;Customer Service&#8221; phone lines today that made me reflect on how often this has been happening recently. It&#8217;s incredibly frustrating to call a company with a problem only to be confronted by an automated system that needs to be defeated to reach someone who can actually help.</p>



<p>When was the last time you called a business and a person picked up with no automated system in between? When was the last time an automated system was able to answer a question that you had that you weren&#8217;t already able to Google the solution to? </p>



<p>Automated phone systems have risen to the point where nearly every business you call will immediately relegate your call to one first in an attempt to not have to actually deal with you. While AI could some day replace the role of Customer Service Representatives, that day is not now.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Minimal Costs, Maximum Marketing, No Value to Customers</h2>



<p>With the interconnectivity of the world growing rapidly, Customer Service is often outsourced to extremely cheap call centers. This can often lead to costs for Customer Service agents being less than the US minimum wage. Even with less than minimum wage employees, companies still choose to not hire enough to avoid multi-hour wait times for customers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8987" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-center-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>On top of minimal costs, wait times are not just music anymore. Advertising and marketing now constantly berate you while you are waiting for help. There is actually an incentive for companies to have multi-hour wait times because it means you will be listening to hours of marketing. Since you are already involved with the company in some way, this marketing ends up being the even more effective &#8220;targeted&#8221; type of marketing. And of course, in between the marketing they will remind you how you can use their other automated system online in an attempt to avoid having to talk to you.</p>



<p>Despite minimal costs and free targeted marketing, these call centers often can&#8217;t even help you. Most of the time they will end up referring you to some online form to go through some automated system or tell you that someone who can actually help you will call you back in the next few days. Their inability to help would be easier to deal with if it didn&#8217;t come with all the marketing and wasted time. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">24/7 Automated Customer Service</h2>



<p>Have you noticed how most of these Customer Service lines tout themselves as being 24/7 service? Like it&#8217;s some big accomplishment that you can call an automated line any time of the day. If a 24/7 automated service can&#8217;t help, it may as well be closed; a closed call center is just as helpful. It&#8217;s so disingenuous to call these automated systems &#8220;24/7 Customer Service,&#8221; but with the prevalence of unsubstantiated claims in marketing, it isn&#8217;t much of a surprise.  </p>



<p>As a computer savvy person, when I call a Customer Service line the chances are I&#8217;ve already exhausted every automated online solution in an attempt to not have to talk with someone. And yet, the first thing I have to do to reach a person who can properly parse my issue is go through the spoken version of what I just did online.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="402" src="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-tree.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8990" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/customer-service-tree.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/customer-service-tree-300x241.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<p>I remember not too long ago that you could just spam &#8220;0&#8221; until the automated system gave up and put you through to someone. I haven&#8217;t found that to be true anymore with modern systems. Now they will just repeat the automated tree choices or sometimes even just hang up on you. On top of that, if you go down the wrong path of the automated tree, sometimes you&#8217;ll end up with a fully automated response with no chance of talking to someone. It&#8217;s actually becoming a skill to be able to reach a real Customer Service rep. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Future of Customer Service</h2>



<p>I don&#8217;t see this getting any better any time soon. Similar to the rise of self-checkouts at grocery stores, society is becoming increasingly accepting of terrible automated systems as the norm. I&#8217;d love to change to a company that doesn&#8217;t employ these automated systems but it is getting harder and harder to find them. If every company in a field is doing something you object to, your only viable option is to not engage with that field at all anymore, which isn&#8217;t really much of an option for many things. </p>



<p>What is there left to do? What power do customers have when every company that exists is doing it? Do I need to start my own bank to avoid having to sit on hold with my bank for hours every time I need help? Do I not use banks? Do I petition the government to intervene? Do I write a blog post complaining about it all?</p>



<p>Because we are forced to deal with it, it becomes normalized. As it becomes normalized, companies push it even further. As companies pushes it further, we are forced to deal with it. They are constantly towing the line where customers will complain about it, but won&#8217;t do anything about it. </p>



<p>We&#8217;re moving quicker every year toward more and more extreme anti-customer practices. Every good business person knows that good Customer Service leads to a more successful business, but the bar for &#8220;good&#8221; is in a constant, sharp decline. </p>



<p>How long before we&#8217;re so tired of the newest cost cutting Customer Service system that we&#8217;re relieved to hear a friendly automated voice ask us to press 1?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torghast is Not Fun and Not Rewarding</title>
		<link>/torghast-is-not-fun-and-not-rewarding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 20:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now that we are a couple months into Shadowlands and the rush has settled down, issues with longevity start to become more obvious. While Torghast started as something fresh and exciting, I&#8217;m starting to struggle to find the motivation to even finish my weekly Soul Ash runs, let alone continue my slow grind through Twisting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Now that we are a couple months into Shadowlands and the rush has settled down, issues with longevity start to become more obvious. While Torghast started as something fresh and exciting, I&#8217;m starting to struggle to find the motivation to even finish my weekly Soul Ash runs, let alone continue my slow grind through Twisting Corridors. </p>



<p>Torghast isn&#8217;t fun. I found myself super excited to try out Torghast on my freshly capped 60s just so I could see what kind of nonsense I could get into with them. But now that I&#8217;ve played through it on multiple classes, I realize that the powers are boringly &#8220;balanced.&#8221; From what I saw of the beta, you used to be able to scale your character to ridiculous levels of power that easily led to some great &#8220;did you see that?&#8221; moments. The Torghast we have now however is no where near as exciting; it&#8217;s too balanced and boring. </p>



<p>Don&#8217;t misunderstand my use of <em>balance </em>here, I know that many classes/specs struggle while some classes excel. What I mean is that runs usually end up being pretty close to the same every time. Due to a lack of Anima power diversity and the relatively small impact most powers have, you end each run at pretty close to the same power level.</p>



<p>Torghast also doesn&#8217;t feel rewarding. Twisting Corridor&#8217;s cosmetic rewards are a good start, but it&#8217;s a one time thing, on one character. Once I finish, I don&#8217;t see myself ever going back into the Twisting Corridors. Even if my friends want help, the idea of another multi-hour run that could very well end in complete failure with nothing to show for it doesn&#8217;t sound fun to me. </p>



<p>Unfortunately fixing one of these problems, rewards or fun, will likely hurt the other. <strong>Is Torghast supposed to be a part of the endgame grind, or is it just for fun? </strong>Blizz needs to pick one, because this conflict is ruining Torghast.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Serious Game Mode &#8211; OR &#8211; Just For Fun</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A New Endgame Mode</h3>



<p>Torghast could be a whole new endgame mode, similar to Raids, PvP, and Mythic+. Adding more difficult content while balancing across classes/specs could make Torghast something people spend a majority of their game time playing. Imagine a Torghast where you actually chose to craft the Torghast +Phatasma legendary first, where you picked your covenant and soulbinds based on which one was best in Torghast. WoW has always lacked challenging single player content. The Mage Tower challenge back in Legion was a great example of a personal challenge. It seems that it was quite well received by the player base who had little to no outlet for challenging content that didn&#8217;t rely on at least one other person. Torghast can be a replayable, challenging, endgame, solo game mode alongside the group based endgame modes we already have.</p>



<p>However, with increased difficulty needs to come increased rewards. Every main game mode can currently stand on its own in regard to gearing. While you can augment your gear through the other main game modes, your character will increase in power by just doing that one type of content. That is currently not true in Torghast. To do well in Torghast, you need to get gear from elsewhere. If Torghast is to become a main game mode, the rewards need to be comparable to other modes. </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Fun Casual Experience</h3>



<p>WoW has continuously moved away from the idea of &#8220;just for fun&#8221; content with every new system introduced being required to keep your character at maximum efficiency. Torghast had the opportunity to be something that you do for fun, rather than because you feel like you are required to to remain relevant. Unfortunately, the fact that legendaries require you to complete many Torghast runs, it&#8217;s not &#8220;just for fun.&#8221; </p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had a few really fun experiences in Torghast that have stuck with me. During the first week of the Torghast event where you can pick and buff the dogs, I had the death explosion of my pet take more than half of the final boss&#8217;s health. My friend recently leveled up his Priest and was excited to show me a build he had gotten that allowed him to one shot the final boss with a single super-buffed Mind Blast. Getting a free Starfall when swapping into Moonkin along with a free Stampeding Roar from cat, when matched with the Stellar Drift talent, makes Balance druid exhilarating. There are some great opportunities for fun in Torghast, but they are the exception when they should be the norm. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/dog-bomb.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="884" height="402" src="/wp-content/uploads/dog-bomb.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9010" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/dog-bomb.jpg 884w, /wp-content/uploads/dog-bomb-300x136.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/dog-bomb-768x349.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 884px) 100vw, 884px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Dog death deals more than half of the boss&#8217;s health</figcaption></figure>



<p>Torghast&#8217;s longevity would be so much better if these types of experiences happened more often. I guess the concern would be that one-shotting bosses is too easy, but isn&#8217;t the point of a game to have fun? Fun can be found in difficulty, yes. But if you are already having fun with the ridiculousness of the situation, difficulty isn&#8217;t really needed. There are plenty of other outlets for difficulty in WoW, but few modes that are just for fun. Another critisim of a just-for-fun Torghast would be that legendaries would be too easy to get. But, is that really an issue? If legendaries should be challenging to earn, why not take Soul Ash out of Torghast and have it only drop from Mythic Raids, Mythic+20s, or 2400+ rated PvP?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other Issues</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rewards For Failure</h3>



<p>I know that many people are against the idea of &#8220;everyone gets a trophy,&#8221; but there needs to be something to show for partial Torghast runs. Torghast&#8217;s binary reward nature of everything or nothing discourages challenging yourself with runs that you aren&#8217;t pretty much guaranteed to win. And if you already know you are going to win, then the run itself becomes superfluous.</p>



<p>Almost every successful Roguelite rewards you for failure. In Hades, for example, you aren&#8217;t expected to complete your first run. You lose, and when you do, you still gain power. That power makes slowly makes you stronger, and eventually you complete the challenge. You are always making progress, even in failure. Even in WoW, we get partial rewards in every other major game mode:</p>



<p><strong>Raids </strong>give loot for every boss killed, not just the final boss. The gear you get from partial completions week after week eventually get you and your raid group enough gear to conquer the boss you are stuck on. </p>



<p><strong>PvP </strong>gives honor for losses. Even if you are a fresh capped 60 without your trinket set bonus, you still get some currency after getting destroyed. Even going into Skirms and dying in the opener over and over gets you closer to better gear and a stronger character.</p>



<p><strong>Normal, Heroic, and Mythic-0 dungeons</strong> give loot per boss, not for completion. Though it doesn&#8217;t happen often, if your group is struggling to finish off a final boss of a dungeon, you at least got a chance at loot from the previous bosses you downed. </p>



<p><strong>Mythic+</strong> is probably the closest to the reward state of Torghast, but even in this elitist gamemode that spawned the concept of Raider.io to filter out bad players in an attempt to minimize wasted time with no rewards, you can still get a reward after you fail the timer. </p>



<p>With rewards offered at every floor boss, or even as a chance from every enemy killed, failure in Torghast will not be as disheartening. Knowing that wiping on a final boss in Twisting Corridors could leave me with nothing to show for the last 3 hours of work getting there is not something I enjoy.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">More Variety For More Replayability</h3>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Anima Powers</h4>



<p>While it was cool to see the powers on my first few playthroughs and fantasize about all the cool stuff I might be able to do, I now know pretty much all of the limited pool of powers each of my classes can get. After a few runs of Torghast, you&#8217;ve likely seen almost every power your specialization has. There need to be more choices to keep runs fresh. By the end of each run, most of my characters end at about the same power level. Especially in Twisted Corridors, where you have an increased chance of getting the rarer powers, you end up with pretty similar builds every run.</p>



<p>Also, many choices don&#8217;t even end up feeling like choices at all. Am I really going to pick &#8220;Mawrats don&#8217;t run away&#8221; over almost anything else? I&#8217;ve tried a full Mawrat build, and can tell you that once you get to the last boss, arguably the most important part of any run, the Mawrat build does not work well with no Mawrats&#8230; </p>



<p>WoW has this choice issue elsewhere too. Similar to talents, gear, spec, covenant, and rotation, there almost always ends up be a &#8220;best&#8221; choice. It makes sense to not make the meta choice if the non-meta choice is more fun, but if I&#8217;m choosing between something like &#8220;puts a DoT on enemies,&#8221; &#8220;attacks deal extra damage,&#8221; or &#8220;your health is increased,&#8221; none of these are engaging at all and the choice should always be which one is &#8220;best&#8221; since none of them are &#8220;fun.&#8221; </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Enemy and Environment Diversity</h4>



<p>Why are there so few types of enemies in Torghast? Lore wise, the Maw is currently where every mortal soul is going, so it would make sense for literally any group or faction that exists in WoW to exist here. And yet, all we get is the Jailer&#8217;s minions, Fae, Kvaldir, and Fire Elementals&#8230; Every wing ends up feeling so similar because there are so few enemy types. A diverse set of enemies would help to keep each run fresh, as certain powers could interact with certain abilities in interesting ways.</p>



<p>One of the coolest things about Shadowlands is that we are in a whole new reality where the perfect world exists for every mortal. I won&#8217;t go too far into my disappointment in the fact that not only do we only see 5 of these worlds, no other worlds are even mentioned. Why not have Torghast be a place to show us glimpses of all the other worlds that exist in the Shadowlands? Each floor could be a new world, or perhaps just an illusion of a ravaged version of a world where the Mawsworn are torturing that world&#8217;s inhabitants. Shadowlands opens a whole new universe of lore, but we&#8217;re seeing such a small portion of it so far. Something needs to be starting to build up the lore of the other worlds that exist in the Shadowlands; why not use Torghast to do so?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Future of Torghast</h2>



<p>Torghast is full of potential. Unfortunately, it currently seems to be going the same way that Island Expeditions in BfA did: a required, boring grind. The conflict between just-for-fun and a challenging, rewarding endgame experience are at odds with each other. If Torghast is to survive, Blizz needs to pick just one.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deimos Arcana Update &#8211; Bonewidow Necramech, Infested Kitguns, and Steel Path Changes</title>
		<link>/deimos-arcana-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 19:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warframe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Deimos Arcana update comes with a new Necramech, new weapons, changes to Steel Essence acquisition, and many other small changes. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://forums.warframe.com/topic/1236257-update-295-deimos-arcana/">Patch 29.5, Deimos Arcana</a>, adds new content to Warframe. This content patch comes with a new Necramech, changes to Steel Essence acquisition, new weapons including Infested Kitguns, and many other small changes. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="bonewidow-necramech">Bonewidow Necramech</h2>



<p>Unlike the Voidrig, the second Necramech to be added to the game is focused on <strong>melee</strong>. The <a href="https://warframe.fandom.com/wiki/Bonewidow">Bonewidow </a>has an exalted melee weapon as its fourth ability, and its other abilities are also focused on melee. </p>



<p>Its blueprints can be acquired from the <a href="/warframe/deimos/necraloid-syndicate/">Necraloid Syndicate</a>, with the main blueprint obtainable at max rank (Rank 3: Odima) for <strong>10,000 standing</strong> and the <strong>four </strong>component blueprints requiring <strong>3,500 standing each</strong>. The component blueprints will require damaged parts obtained from <a href="/warframe/deimos/isolation-vaults/">isolation vaults</a>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="infested-kitguns">Infested Kitguns</h2>



<p>Infested Kitguns are primary and secondary weapons that are built from components just like their Fortuna counterparts. There are new Infested style <strong>chambers, grips, and loaders</strong>. These parts can be purchased from <a href="/warframe/deimos/entrati-syndicate#father">Father</a> for Entrati Standing. Once purchased, talk with Rude Zudd in Fortuna to put the gun together. You can mix and match Kitgun components from Fortuna too. Check out the <a href="https://warframe.fandom.com/wiki/Kitgun#Primary">Kitgun page on the wiki</a> for more specifics on each part.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/infested-kitgun.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="792" src="/wp-content/uploads/infested-kitgun-1024x792.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9205" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/infested-kitgun-1024x792.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/infested-kitgun-300x232.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/infested-kitgun-768x594.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/infested-kitgun.jpg 1071w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Infested Kitguns &#8211; Primaries and Secondaries</figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="steel-path-incursions">Steel Path Incursions</h2>



<p>Deimos Arcana adds a <strong>new way to acquire Steel Essence</strong>. Every day there will be five Steel Path incursions that will reward Steel Essence when completed. These missions will be available to everyone who has access to the Steel Path, even if the node has not been unlocked, helping with matchmaking. </p>



<p>In addition, any Steel Path mission can now spawn Acolytes. These Acolytes will drop two Steel Essences when defeated, but will run away if they down you. Teshin&#8217;s inventory has been updated with new wares to spend Steel Essence on, including rare items like <strong>Umbra Forma</strong> blueprints.</p>



<p>Check out our <a href="/warframe/steel-path/">Steel Path guide</a> for tips on this difficult game mode.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/steel-path-incursions.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="708" height="818" src="/wp-content/uploads/steel-path-incursions.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9371" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/steel-path-incursions.jpg 708w, /wp-content/uploads/steel-path-incursions-260x300.jpg 260w" sizes="(max-width: 708px) 100vw, 708px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Steel Path Incursions</figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="isolation-vault-changes-in-deimos-arcana">Isolation Vault Changes in Deimos Arcana</h2>



<p>Deimos Arcana focuses a lot on changes to <a href="/warframe/deimos/isolation-vaults/">Isolation Vaults</a>, adding four new ruins. New items gave been added as rewards for isolation vaults. There are also some new encounters in isolation vaults, offering some variety for extended runs. The <strong>speed of Loid has been increased</strong>, while his health has been decreased. Scintillants inside the vaults now have a chance to respawn, so if you get the same vault on an extended run, you can still get more. </p>



<p>You now have a chance to fight the new Bonewidow Necramech instead of just the normal Voidrig. The difficulty of these enemy Necramechs has also been adjusted by giving them many of the <strong>characteristics of Kuva Liches</strong>, like diminishing returns on status effects instead of immunity. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="entrati-syndicate-changes-in-deimos-arcana">Entrati Syndicate Changes in Deimos Arcana</h2>



<p>In addition to the items that have been added as part of this patch, the <a href="/warframe/deimos/entrati-syndicate/">Entrati Syndicate</a> has had some other small changes. You can now obtain every family member&#8217;s tokens from Grandmother through her new &#8220;Mend the Family&#8221; option. This gives an alternate way to obtain tokens other than engaging with that specific family member&#8217;s content. </p>



<p>There is a new evergreen use for <a href="/warframe/deimos/necraloid-syndicate/">Necraloid Syndicate</a> standing. You can now exchange <strong>50,000 Necraloid Standing</strong> for a Ayatan Sculpture with a base value of 450 Endo. With four Cyan and one Amber Ayatan installed, it has a value of <strong>3000 Endo</strong>. </p>



<p>Two new mods have been added to Sons inventory. Martyr Symbiosis gives Vulpaphyla the ability to store health from enemy deaths and heal their master. Volatile Parasite spawns a parasite that attaches to enemies, forcing other enemies to attack it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/deimos-arcana-mods.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="401" height="252" src="/wp-content/uploads/deimos-arcana-mods.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8992" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/deimos-arcana-mods.jpg 401w, /wp-content/uploads/deimos-arcana-mods-300x189.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">New companion mods</figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous </h2>



<ul>
<li>You can purchase a cosmetic outfit for your Sentinel companion to make it look like Loid</li>



<li>You can build a new Infested K-Drive with parts purchased from <a href="/warframe/deimos/entrati-syndicate#grandmother">Grandmother</a></li>



<li>You can now view the current cycle in the corresponding hub
<ul>
<li>Vome/Fass cycle in the Necralisk; current temperature in Fortuna; time of day in Cetus</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>There are new conservation and fishing creatures in the Cambion Drifts</li>



<li><a href="/warframe/deimos/conservation/">Conservation </a>targets now reward more tags based on level of success</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/infested-kdrive.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="488" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/infested-kdrive-488x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9204" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/infested-kdrive-488x1024.jpg 488w, /wp-content/uploads/infested-kdrive-143x300.jpg 143w, /wp-content/uploads/infested-kdrive.jpg 494w" sizes="(max-width: 488px) 100vw, 488px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Infested K-Drive</figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Good Are Dynamax Adventures</title>
		<link>/how-good-are-dynamax-adventures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 20:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pokemon: Sword & Shield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are the new Dynamax Adventures in the Crown Tundra a good addition to Pokemon Sword and Shield? My thoughts on this new legendary experience.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dynamax Adventures are a new type of content added in the <a href="https://swordshield.pokemon.com/en-us/expansionpass/the-crown-tundra/">Crown Tundra DLC</a> for Pokemon Sword and Shield. This system is the only way to capture the returning legendaries, other than the Regis, in the Crown Tundra. With almost 50 legendaries, Dynamax Adventures will take you a while to complete.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Do Dynamax Adventures Work?</h2>



<p>Shortly into the Crown Tundra expansion, you will unlock this new system. Each run will pit you against multiple Pokemon, with a guaranteed legendary at the end. You will have a chance to catch the legendary if you defeat it. However, you can only a capture each legendary once. You will not get the option to capture a legendary you have already captured.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-description.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="706" height="501" src="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-description.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9012" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-description.jpg 706w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-description-300x213.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 100vw, 706px" /></a></figure>



<p>Rather than bringing in your own Pokemon, your team will check out rental Pokemon with set templates. Each Pokemon you defeat along the way to the last fight can be exchanged for your current rental Pokemon. HP, PP, and statuses all carry over between fights.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rental Pokemon</h2>



<p>You will not be able to bring your own Pokemon into Dynamax Adventures. Instead you and your team will be using <a href="https://www.serebii.net/swordshield/dynamaxadventurespokemon.shtml">rental Pokemon templates</a>. There are only a limited number of Pokemon that can be used in this setting. Obtaining them for your run is left up to RNG. These templates ensure that in group play you will not get matched up with someone with a &#8220;bad&#8221; Pokemon. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-rental.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-rental-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9015" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-rental-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-rental-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-rental-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-rental.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pokemon are rented in Dynamax Adventures</figcaption></figure>



<p>While it is nice to be able to play with Pokemon I would not otherwise use, I wish I could use my Pokemon instead. You catch all these legendaries, but can&#8217;t even use them in this format. Using Pokemon that aren&#8217;t mine makes me feel a bit disconnected from the fights. Most runs end up feeling more like RNG than skill.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Legendary Pokemon as Rewards</h2>



<p>The main rewards from Dynamax Adventures are Legendary Pokemon. Every Legendary is obtainable in the Crown Tundra. It&#8217;s great that these Pokemon have been added, but their use is limited. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-reward.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-reward-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9016" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-reward-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-reward-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-reward-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-reward.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Legendary Pokemon are the main reward from Dynamax Adventures</figcaption></figure>



<p>With so many of them, they feel a lot less exciting to capture than they were originally. Many of these Pokemon used to be at the end of extensive quest chains that culminated in battles with dedicated arenas and music. Instead, now you&#8217;ll be fighting every legendary in the same boring Dynamax Den arena with a slightly remixed version of the boring Dynamax Den music. Overall, the ease of access and the shear number of legendaries you&#8217;ll be capturing remove a lot of the &#8220;legendary&#8221; feeling from them. </p>



<p>They also, generally, cannot be used in competitive battles. There are some events and formats where legendaries can be used. But, for the most part you won&#8217;t be able to bring your new OP Pokemon into ranked fights. Perhaps there is some use for them in the new Galarian Star Tournament. However, by the time you&#8217;ve captured these Pokemon you&#8217;ll already be in the endgame of Sword and Shield, limiting the use of these legendaries. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dynamax Adventures Additional Rewards</h2>



<p>Completing a Dynamax Adventure will also reward you with the new currency, Dynite Ore. This currency can be spent on a few useful items like Beast Balls, vitamins, and the new <a href="https://www.serebii.net/itemdex/abilitypatch.shtml">Ability Patch</a>. Dynite Ore is a decent reward and the rate you get them from adventures is ok. </p>



<p>In addition to legendaries, Dynamax Aventures are a good way to shiny hunt. Unlike normal Max Raid Battles, the Pokemon in these fights do not gain shields at certain health breakpoints, making the fights pretty quick. It is possible to obtain shiny versions of the legendaries too, but you can only catch one of each. If you are planning on shiny hunting legendaries, you&#8217;ll have to pass on every non-shiny until you get lucky.</p>



<p>Unlike Max Raid Battles, you don&#8217;t get TRs or EXP candies. Despite being a good source of Dynite Ore, once you capture each legendary, you&#8217;ll have very little incentive to continue doing Dynamax Adventures. You can trade your Dynite Ore for Armorite Ore, which can then by converted into Watts at Digging Pa. For more on this process, check out our guide on <a href="/farm-watts-in-isle-of-armor/">Watt Farming</a>. Unfortunately, the exchange rate isn&#8217;t great and if you are targeting Watts specifically; it&#8217;s probably best to just farm the Armorite Ore instead. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Playing With a Team</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Real Players</h3>



<p>Dynamax Adventures encourage playing in a group with other players. Sometimes these fights can be quite difficult with rental Pokemon. Playing with others is the best way to complete these challenges. I&#8217;ve generally had good experiences with the groups I have had. But, Sword and Shield has always had an issue with player interactions. </p>



<p>Other than the few choices you make during your run, you can&#8217;t interact with the other players at all. Pokemon, and Nintendo in general, has always tried to limit the ability of players to be toxic to one another. However, with almost no interaction, the other players in my team might as well be intelligent bots. Even something as simple as an emote system would bring some life into these groups. Though, I&#8217;d probably end up spamming &#8220;Good Job!&#8221; when someone uses another water move into Maractus&#8217;s Storm Drain&#8230;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-path.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-path-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9014" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-path-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-path-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-path-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/dynamax-adventures-path.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Non-Playable Characters</h3>



<p>If you can&#8217;t or don&#8217;t want to play with other real players, the game will match you up with NPCs. Luckily these bots aren&#8217;t as bad as those in Max Raid Battles. They will be using the same rental Pokemon that you have access to, which are mostly decent. However, they still make frustratingly bad decisions, especially when it comes to status moves and two-turn moves. </p>



<p>Playing with NPCs does mean that you get to pick the path. This lets you pick the Pokemon that will be most useful in the final battle. However, you can&#8217;t force them to pick the Pokemon that you capture along the way. Even if those Pokemon would be clearly superior than their current Pokemon, the bots might not pick them. When playing with NPCs, your success is much more reliant on RNG than when playing with other players. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dynamax Adventures Summary</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pros</h3>



<p>Dynamax Adventures are a good addition to Pokemon Sword and Shield. It&#8217;s nice to be able to catch all the legendaries of previous games. Rental Pokemon make you diversify your Pokemon choices, keeping it fresh (for a while). </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cons</h3>



<p>Once you have one of each legendary, there is little reason to continue doing these. Many runs feel that they are in the hands of RNG rather than skill. You are encouraged to play with others, but can&#8217;t interact with them. NPCs still make terrible decisions and can turn a good run into a failure with no mistakes on your part. Catching legendaries in this format does not feel &#8220;legendary.&#8221;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/dynamax-adventures-catch-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1342"/></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Access the Crown Tundra</title>
		<link>/access-crown-tundra/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 05:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokemon: Sword & Shield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learn how to get to the Crown Tundra and start your legendary adventure in Pokemon Sword and Shield's second expansion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="https://swordshield.pokemon.com/en-us/expansionpass/the-crown-tundra/">Crown Tundra</a> is the second expansion for Pokemon Sword and Shield. It includes a whole new zone to explore south of the original zone. It is full of returning Pokemon from previous games, including legendries. This guide will show you how to get to the Crown Tundra.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Purchase the Crown Tundra Expansion</h2>



<p>The Crown Tundra is paid DLC for Pokemon Sword and Shield. To go to the new area, you will need to buy the expansion. The easiest way to do this is through the Nintendo eShop, but this will require an internet connection. You do not need the paid service, Nintendo Switch Online, to make this purchase. </p>



<p>You can navigate to the purchase page in multiple ways. Opening the Nintendo eShop through the Switch homepage and searching for Pokemon Sword or Pokemon Shield will take you to their respective pages. You can also press the &#8220;+&#8221; button on the icon for Sword or Shield to bring up its menu. Under &#8220;Software Information&#8221; select &#8220;Nintendo eShop.&#8221;</p>



<p>From the main page for the version of the game you own, scroll down to see the DLCs available for purchase. Currently, you cannot buy the Crown Tundra on its own; you will have to purchase the Expansion Pass that also includes<a href="https://swordshield.pokemon.com/en-us/expansionpass/the-isle-of-armor/"> Isle of Armor</a>.</p>



<p>You can also purchase physical copies of the game plus the expansion pass at Nintendo&#8217;s website for both <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/pokemon-sword-and-pokemon-sword-expansion-pass-switch/">Sword </a>and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/pokemon-shield-and-pokemon-shield-expansion-pass-switch/">Shield</a>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Go to the Wedgehurst Train Station</h2>



<p>Once you have purchased the expansion, you will receive a notification upon loading into the game that you are ready to set off to the Crown Tundra. You will also receive a &#8220;Crown Pass&#8221; key item that allows you to select the new destination at the train station. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-pass.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="706" height="574" src="/wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-pass.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8214" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-pass.jpg 706w, /wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-pass-300x244.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 706px) 100vw, 706px" /></a></figure>



<p>Similar to the Isle of Armor, you will need to go to the Wedgehurt Train Station. This is the first city that you encountered in the story, just north of Route 01. The train station is on the southern part of the city. Once inside, present you Crown Pass to the ticket NPC and select the Crown Tundra Station. If you haven&#8217;t yet done the opening to Isle of Armor, you will have to catch the slowpoke first. </p>



<p>Upon arriving, you Pokedex will be updated with all of the new Crown Tundra specific Pokemon. Just leave the station and start your legendary adventure!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-station.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="445" src="/wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-station-1024x445.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8215" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-station-1024x445.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-station-300x130.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-station-768x334.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/access-crown-tundra-station.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G-Max Coalossal Steam Engine Sweeper (Sw/Sh Doubles)</title>
		<link>/coalossal-swsh-doubles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 07:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Builds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokemon: Sword & Shield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[G-Max Coalossal can outspeed and OHKO almost anything with this Steam Engine Weakness Policy doubles team for Pokemon Sword &#038; Shield. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This doubles strategy makes use of <a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/coalossal/">Coalossal&#8217;s</a> ability <a href="https://www.serebii.net/abilitydex/steamengine.shtml">Steam Engine</a> ability to give it a huge speed boost while also doubling its Special Attack through <a href="https://www.serebii.net/itemdex/weaknesspolicy.shtml">Weakness Policy</a>, allowing Coalossal to OHKO most Pokemon with its great type coverage. It also sets up G-Max Volcalith to whittle down defensive opponents.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">G-Max Coalossal&#8217;s Build</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-stats.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="927" height="550" src="/wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-stats.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8979" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-stats.jpg 927w, /wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-stats-300x178.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-stats-768x456.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 927px) 100vw, 927px" /></a></figure>



<p>Coalossal makes up for its terrible speed with great special attack and good bulk. With a base stat of 110 HP, it is a great target to Dynamax since Dynamaxing doubles the Pokemon&#8217;s health. However, it has a 4x weakness to Water, meaning that hard hitting Water moves can still OHKO it.  </p>



<p>Coalossal&#8217;s nature and EV distribution is left a bit up to choice. The most important stats for Coalossal are Special Attack, Speed, and HP. Focusing on Special Attack and Speed give Coalossal the best chance of being able to OHKO a Pokemon before it gets its turn. However, in situations where you won&#8217;t be able to OHKO or the opponent has priority moves, the extra bulk from HP will significantly increase how long Coalossal lives. HP is also a great choice if you expect that your opponent will be able to shut down your Water Enabler (see <a href="#counters">Counters</a>). </p>



<p>You can also min/max a bit with the SpA and Spe values to just perfectly outspeed or OHKO the Pokemon you expect to be up against, allowing you to put more EVs into HP. Since it is tough to account for every possible scenario, especially with the prevalence of speed increases like Max Airstream, I suggest just maxing EVs in SpA and Spe, even if it ends up being a bit overkill.</p>



<p>The moves are chosen to maximize G-Max damage; Coalossal will not be very effective when not G-Maxed, but if you get three G-Max moves off with this build, you are likely doing well.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">G-Max <a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/coalossal/">Coalossal</a></h4>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><tbody><tr><td>Nature</td><td>Timid (+Spe, -Atk)<br>Modest (+SpA, -Atk)</td></tr><tr><td>Ability</td><td>Steam Engine</td></tr><tr><td>Item</td><td>Weakness Policy</td></tr><tr><td>EVs</td><td>SpA: 252<br>Spe: 252<br>HP: 4</td></tr><tr><td>Moves</td><td>Meteor Beam (G-Max Volcalith)<br>Fire Blast (Max Flare)<br>Solar Beam (Max Overgrowth)<br>Earth Power (Max Quake)</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-moves.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="533" height="176" src="/wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-moves.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8978" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-moves.jpg 533w, /wp-content/uploads/coalossal-swsh-doubles-moves-300x99.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 533px) 100vw, 533px" /></a></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Water Enabler&#8217;s Build</h2>



<p>To trigger Coalossal&#8217;s Steam Engine and Weakness policy at the same time, you will want to hit it with a water move. There are two good options for water moves to use on your Coalossal &#8211; Aqua Jet and Surf.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://serebii.net/attackdex-swsh/aquajet.shtml">Aqua Jet</a></h3>



<p>The best option to guarantee you outspeed your opponent is Aqua Jet, a <strong>+1 priority</strong> water move. Aqua Jet allows your Water Enabler to bypass speed concerns, opening up a more diverse set of builds, including bulky supports. </p>



<p>Where Aqua Jet will have issues when compared to Surf is against Follow Me and Rage Powder. These moves will redirect your Aqua Jet into the other Pokemon instead of Coalossal. See <a href="#counters">Counters </a>for more on this.</p>



<p>A couple good options to consider for an Aqua Jet Water Enabler:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/azumarill/">Azumarill </a>&#8211; 50 Atk, 100 HP, bulky, Light Screen, Grass absorb</li>



<li><a href="https://serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/clawitzer/">Clawitzer </a>&#8211; 73 Atk, 120 SpA, solid Special Attacker</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/azumarill">Azumarill</a></h4>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><tbody><tr><td>Nature</td><td>Modest (+SpA, -Atk)</td></tr><tr><td>Ability</td><td>Sap Sipper</td></tr><tr><td>Item</td><td>Leftovers<br>Wacan Berry<br>Kebia Berry<br>Sitrus Berry</td></tr><tr><td>IVs</td><td>Atk: 0</td></tr><tr><td>EVs</td><td>HP: 252<br>SpA: 252<br>Def/SpD: 4</td></tr><tr><td>Moves</td><td>Aqua Jet<br>Light Screen<br>Hydro Pump / Scald<br>Hyper Voice / Ice Beam</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><a href="https://serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/clawitzer/">Clawitzer</a></h4>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><tbody><tr><td>Nature</td><td>Modest (+SpA, -Atk)</td></tr><tr><td>Ability</td><td>Mega Launcher</td></tr><tr><td>Item</td><td>Life Orb</td></tr><tr><td>IVs</td><td>Atk: 0</td></tr><tr><td>EVs</td><td>SpA: 252<br>Spe: 252<br>HP: 4</td></tr><tr><td>Moves</td><td>Aqua Jet<br>Scald / Water Pulse<br>Ice Beam / Dragon Pulse<br>Dark Pulse / Aura Sphere</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.serebii.net/attackdex-sm/surf.shtml">Surf</a></h3>



<p>Another option instead of Aqua Jet is to bring Surf on a fast Pokemon. Similar to Aqua Jet, you will want this move to hit for very little. The benefit of Surf over Aqua Jet is Surf <strong>hits the entire field</strong>. This ignores one of the major counters to an Aqua Jet setup, Follow Me and Rage Powder. The AoE of Surf also hits opponents, removing their Focus Sashes before Coalossal gets its first hit.</p>



<p>The issue with Surf is that your snabler is more vulnerable to priority moves and fast Pokemon. Whimsicott&#8217;s Trickster priority Tailwind can make many Pokemon faster than your Water Enabler, potentially OHKOing it before it gets Surf off. See <a href="#counters">Counters </a>for more on this.</p>



<p>Some Pokemon to consider as Surf Water Enablers:</p>



<ul id="block-913754ec-e6f8-4707-822f-69a39aecb32b">
<li><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/weavile/">Weavile </a>&#8211; 125 Speed, 45 Special Attack, non-STAB Water</li>



<li><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/dragapult/">Dragapult </a>&#8211; 142 Speed, 100 Special Attack, non-STAB Water</li>



<li><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/barraskewda/">Barraskewda</a> &#8211; 136 Speed, 60 Special Attack</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/weavile/">Weavile</a></h4>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><tbody><tr><td>Nature</td><td>Jolly (+Spe, -SpA)</td></tr><tr><td>Ability</td><td>Pressure</td></tr><tr><td>Item</td><td>Focus Sash<br>Life Orb</td></tr><tr><td>IVs</td><td>SpA: 0</td></tr><tr><td>EVs</td><td>Atk: 252<br>Spe: 252<br>HP: 4</td></tr><tr><td>Moves</td><td>Surf<br>Icicle Crash<br>Ice Shard<br>Knock Off</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/dragapult/">Dragapult</a></h4>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><tbody><tr><td>Nature</td><td>Jolly (+Spe, -SpA)</td></tr><tr><td>Ability</td><td>Infiltrator<br>Clear Body</td></tr><tr><td>Item</td><td>Focus Sash<br>Life Orb<br>Colbur Berry</td></tr><tr><td>IVs</td><td>SpA: 0</td></tr><tr><td>EVs</td><td>Atk: 252<br>Spe: 252<br>HP: 4</td></tr><tr><td>Moves</td><td>Surf<br>Phantom Force<br>Dragon Claw/Darts<br>Sucker Punch</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokedex-swsh/barraskewda/">Barraskewda</a></h4>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><tbody><tr><td>Nature</td><td>Jolly (+Spe, -SpA)</td></tr><tr><td>Ability</td><td>Propeller Tail</td></tr><tr><td>Item</td><td>Focus Sash</td></tr><tr><td>IVs</td><td>SpA: 0</td></tr><tr><td>EVs</td><td>Atk: 252<br>Spe: 252<br>HP: 4</td></tr><tr><td>Moves</td><td>Surf<br>Liquidation<br>Close Combat<br>Psychic Fangs</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Minimize Damage</h3>



<p>Whether you pick Aqua Jet, Surf, or any other water move, you will want it to hit for as little as possible to avoid dealing unnecessary damage to your Coalossal. This means that you should have a 0 IV (&#8220;No Good&#8221;) in the associated damage stat (Attack for Aqua Jet and Special Attack for Surf). This will keep your Coalossal as healthy as possible and potentially allow it to take a few hits.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Strategy: Attack Your Coalossal With Water</h2>



<p>In an ideal opening turn (with no counters), G-Max your Coalossal and aim to OHKO any threats to Coalossal, like water types. If you don&#8217;t need to pick a specific move to guarantee a kill, try to set up G-Max Volcalith as soon as possible. Volcalith&#8217;s 1/6 health per turn to both opponents adds up quickly and counters any Focus Sash they may have.</p>



<p>With your Water Enabler. hit Coalossal with the water ability to trigger Steam Engine and Weakness Policy. Steam Engine will make Coalossal faster than most Pokemon, especially on turn one before they&#8217;ve had much of a chance to setup. Weakness Policy will give a +2 to Coalossal&#8217;s Special Attack, effectively doubling the amount of damage it deals.  </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="counters">G-Max Coalossal Counters</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Focus Sash Water Attacker</h3>



<p>A Focus Sashed Pokemon with a powerful water type move can OHKO Coalossal. Remember that Coalossal takes 4x damage from water.  Coalossal can outspeed almost any Pokemon once Steam Engine is active and G-Max Volcalith will finish off any sashed Pokemon at the end of the turn. However, you won&#8217;t be able to stop a Pokemon with a Focus Sash from hitting Coalossal at least once. </p>



<p>To account for this, you can bring Fake Out on your Water Enabler and try to take out the sashed Pokemon without Weakness Policy. You might consider switching in a Pokemon that resists or absorbs water and bring Coalossal back once the threat is gone. The issue with Focus Sash is that you won&#8217;t know for sure if a Pokemon has one. Pokemon that are likely to have a Focus Sash are hard hitting but low health &#8216;glass cannons&#8217; like Barraskewda.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fake Out</h3>



<p>Fake Out can stop you Water Enabler from activating Coalossal. This will not only stop Weakness Policy on Coalossal, but also block the activation of Steam Engine. Your opponent&#8217;s other Pokemon can potentially take Coalossal down before it gets to do anything. </p>



<p>The best way to deal with a Fake Out starter is to replace one of Coalossal&#8217;s moves with Protect. Use Protect on your first turn and do the combo on the second. Your opponent may go for you Water Enabler though, so a Protect, Fake Out, or a Focus Sash can help get them to the next turn. The issue here is that you&#8217;ll be losing one of your coverage moves on Coalossal, though having Max Guard against other threats is always nice. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-vivid-purple-color has-css-opacity has-vivid-purple-background-color has-background"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Water Enabler Counters</h3>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Redirect &#8211; Aqua Jet Counter</h4>



<p>Aqua Jet is a targeted ability. If your opponent uses Follow Me or any other redirect move, Aqua Jet will attack the new target instead of Coalossal. Redirect moves have a higher priority than Aqua Jet, so you won&#8217;t be able to go before it. If you don&#8217;t deal with a redirector, they will likely redirect the next turn as well.</p>



<p>This is very hard to deal with on an Aqua Jet setup. Barraskewda can learn Aqua Jet and has the ability Propeller Tail, which ignores redirects. However, Barraskewda hits very hard with Aqua Jet, even with a 0 IV, so be careful hitting your Coalossal with it. For other Pokemon, the best way to get around it is to take out the redirector on the first turn and hope that your opponents other Pokemon doesn&#8217;t hit too hard.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Fast Pokemon &#8211; Surf Counter</h4>



<p>Surf is not a priority move. Your opponent can go before you and potentially OHKO your Water Enabler or Coalossal before you get a chance to activate Steam Engine. </p>



<p>A Focus Sash on your Water Enabler can keep them alive through at least one hit. Picking a high speed Surf Pokemon is important to not run into this counter too often.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
