<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World of Warcraft &#8211; MarvWeb</title>
	<atom:link href="https://https://marvweb.github.io/category/games/world-of-warcraft/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 20:01:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Torghast is Not Fun and Not Rewarding</title>
		<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/torghast-is-not-fun-and-not-rewarding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 20:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now that we are a couple months into Shadowlands and the rush has settled down, issues with longevity start to become more obvious. While Torghast started as something fresh and exciting, I&#8217;m starting to struggle to find the motivation to even finish my weekly Soul Ash runs, let alone continue my slow grind through Twisting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Now that we are a couple months into Shadowlands and the rush has settled down, issues with longevity start to become more obvious. While Torghast started as something fresh and exciting, I&#8217;m starting to struggle to find the motivation to even finish my weekly Soul Ash runs, let alone continue my slow grind through Twisting Corridors. </p>



<p>Torghast isn&#8217;t fun. I found myself super excited to try out Torghast on my freshly capped 60s just so I could see what kind of nonsense I could get into with them. But now that I&#8217;ve played through it on multiple classes, I realize that the powers are boringly &#8220;balanced.&#8221; From what I saw of the beta, you used to be able to scale your character to ridiculous levels of power that easily led to some great &#8220;did you see that?&#8221; moments. The Torghast we have now however is no where near as exciting; it&#8217;s too balanced and boring. </p>



<p>Don&#8217;t misunderstand my use of <em>balance </em>here, I know that many classes/specs struggle while some classes excel. What I mean is that runs usually end up being pretty close to the same every time. Due to a lack of Anima power diversity and the relatively small impact most powers have, you end each run at pretty close to the same power level.</p>



<p>Torghast also doesn&#8217;t feel rewarding. Twisting Corridor&#8217;s cosmetic rewards are a good start, but it&#8217;s a one time thing, on one character. Once I finish, I don&#8217;t see myself ever going back into the Twisting Corridors. Even if my friends want help, the idea of another multi-hour run that could very well end in complete failure with nothing to show for it doesn&#8217;t sound fun to me. </p>



<p>Unfortunately fixing one of these problems, rewards or fun, will likely hurt the other. <strong>Is Torghast supposed to be a part of the endgame grind, or is it just for fun? </strong>Blizz needs to pick one, because this conflict is ruining Torghast.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Serious Game Mode &#8211; OR &#8211; Just For Fun</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A New Endgame Mode</h3>



<p>Torghast could be a whole new endgame mode, similar to Raids, PvP, and Mythic+. Adding more difficult content while balancing across classes/specs could make Torghast something people spend a majority of their game time playing. Imagine a Torghast where you actually chose to craft the Torghast +Phatasma legendary first, where you picked your covenant and soulbinds based on which one was best in Torghast. WoW has always lacked challenging single player content. The Mage Tower challenge back in Legion was a great example of a personal challenge. It seems that it was quite well received by the player base who had little to no outlet for challenging content that didn&#8217;t rely on at least one other person. Torghast can be a replayable, challenging, endgame, solo game mode alongside the group based endgame modes we already have.</p>



<p>However, with increased difficulty needs to come increased rewards. Every main game mode can currently stand on its own in regard to gearing. While you can augment your gear through the other main game modes, your character will increase in power by just doing that one type of content. That is currently not true in Torghast. To do well in Torghast, you need to get gear from elsewhere. If Torghast is to become a main game mode, the rewards need to be comparable to other modes. </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Fun Casual Experience</h3>



<p>WoW has continuously moved away from the idea of &#8220;just for fun&#8221; content with every new system introduced being required to keep your character at maximum efficiency. Torghast had the opportunity to be something that you do for fun, rather than because you feel like you are required to to remain relevant. Unfortunately, the fact that legendaries require you to complete many Torghast runs, it&#8217;s not &#8220;just for fun.&#8221; </p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had a few really fun experiences in Torghast that have stuck with me. During the first week of the Torghast event where you can pick and buff the dogs, I had the death explosion of my pet take more than half of the final boss&#8217;s health. My friend recently leveled up his Priest and was excited to show me a build he had gotten that allowed him to one shot the final boss with a single super-buffed Mind Blast. Getting a free Starfall when swapping into Moonkin along with a free Stampeding Roar from cat, when matched with the Stellar Drift talent, makes Balance druid exhilarating. There are some great opportunities for fun in Torghast, but they are the exception when they should be the norm. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dog-bomb.jpg" alt="Dog death deals more than half of the boss's health" class="wp-image-1529"/><figcaption>Dog death deals more than half of the boss&#8217;s health</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Torghast&#8217;s longevity would be so much better if these types of experiences happened more often. I guess the concern would be that one-shotting bosses is too easy, but isn&#8217;t the point of a game to have fun? Fun can be found in difficulty, yes. But if you are already having fun with the ridiculousness of the situation, difficulty isn&#8217;t really needed. There are plenty of other outlets for difficulty in WoW, but few modes that are just for fun. Another critisim of a just-for-fun Torghast would be that legendaries would be too easy to get. But, is that really an issue? If legendaries should be challenging to earn, why not take Soul Ash out of Torghast and have it only drop from Mythic Raids, Mythic+20s, or 2400+ rated PvP?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other Issues</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rewards For Failure</h3>



<p>I know that many people are against the idea of &#8220;everyone gets a trophy,&#8221; but there needs to be something to show for partial Torghast runs. Torghast&#8217;s binary reward nature of everything or nothing discourages challenging yourself with runs that you aren&#8217;t pretty much guaranteed to win. And if you already know you are going to win, then the run itself becomes superfluous.</p>



<p>Almost every successful Roguelite rewards you for failure. In Hades, for example, you aren&#8217;t expected to complete your first run. You lose, and when you do, you still gain power. That power makes slowly makes you stronger, and eventually you complete the challenge. You are always making progress, even in failure. Even in WoW, we get partial rewards in every other major game mode:</p>



<p><strong>Raids </strong>give loot for every boss killed, not just the final boss. The gear you get from partial completions week after week eventually get you and your raid group enough gear to conquer the boss you are stuck on. </p>



<p><strong>PvP </strong>gives honor for losses. Even if you are a fresh capped 60 without your trinket set bonus, you still get some currency after getting destroyed. Even going into Skirms and dying in the opener over and over gets you closer to better gear and a stronger character.</p>



<p><strong>Normal, Heroic, and Mythic-0 dungeons</strong> give loot per boss, not for completion. Though it doesn&#8217;t happen often, if your group is struggling to finish off a final boss of a dungeon, you at least got a chance at loot from the previous bosses you downed. </p>



<p><strong>Mythic+</strong> is probably the closest to the reward state of Torghast, but even in this elitist gamemode that spawned the concept of Raider.io to filter out bad players in an attempt to minimize wasted time with no rewards, you can still get a reward after you fail the timer. </p>



<p>With rewards offered at every floor boss, or even as a chance from every enemy killed, failure in Torghast will not be as disheartening. Knowing that wiping on a final boss in Twisting Corridors could leave me with nothing to show for the last 3 hours of work getting there is not something I enjoy.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">More Variety For More Replayability</h3>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Anima Powers</h4>



<p>While it was cool to see the powers on my first few playthroughs and fantasize about all the cool stuff I might be able to do, I now know pretty much all of the limited pool of powers each of my classes can get. After a few runs of Torghast, you&#8217;ve likely seen almost every power your specialization has. There need to be more choices to keep runs fresh. By the end of each run, most of my characters end at about the same power level. Especially in Twisted Corridors, where you have an increased chance of getting the rarer powers, you end up with pretty similar builds every run.</p>



<p>Also, many choices don&#8217;t even end up feeling like choices at all. Am I really going to pick &#8220;Mawrats don&#8217;t run away&#8221; over almost anything else? I&#8217;ve tried a full Mawrat build, and can tell you that once you get to the last boss, arguably the most important part of any run, the Mawrat build does not work well with no Mawrats&#8230; </p>



<p>WoW has this choice issue elsewhere too. Similar to talents, gear, spec, covenant, and rotation, there almost always ends up be a &#8220;best&#8221; choice. It makes sense to not make the meta choice if the non-meta choice is more fun, but if I&#8217;m choosing between something like &#8220;puts a DoT on enemies,&#8221; &#8220;attacks deal extra damage,&#8221; or &#8220;your health is increased,&#8221; none of these are engaging at all and the choice should always be which one is &#8220;best&#8221; since none of them are &#8220;fun.&#8221; </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Enemy and Environment Diversity</h4>



<p>Why are there so few types of enemies in Torghast? Lore wise, the Maw is currently where every mortal soul is going, so it would make sense for literally any group or faction that exists in WoW to exist here. And yet, all we get is the Jailer&#8217;s minions, Fae, Kvaldir, and Fire Elementals&#8230; Every wing ends up feeling so similar because there are so few enemy types. A diverse set of enemies would help to keep each run fresh, as certain powers could interact with certain abilities in interesting ways.</p>



<p>One of the coolest things about Shadowlands is that we are in a whole new reality where the perfect world exists for every mortal. I won&#8217;t go too far into my disappointment in the fact that not only do we only see 5 of these worlds, no other worlds are even mentioned. Why not have Torghast be a place to show us glimpses of all the other worlds that exist in the Shadowlands? Each floor could be a new world, or perhaps just an illusion of a ravaged version of a world where the Mawsworn are torturing that world&#8217;s inhabitants. Shadowlands opens a whole new universe of lore, but we&#8217;re seeing such a small portion of it so far. Something needs to be starting to build up the lore of the other worlds that exist in the Shadowlands; why not use Torghast to do so?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Future of Torghast</h2>



<p>Torghast is full of potential. Unfortunately, it currently seems to be going the same way that Island Expeditions in BfA did: a required, boring grind. The conflict between just-for-fun and a challenging, rewarding endgame experience are at odds with each other. If Torghast is to survive, Blizz needs to pick just one.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shadowlands Twink Tips</title>
		<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/shadowlands-twink/</link>
					<comments>https://https://marvweb.github.io/shadowlands-twink/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 08:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Builds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twinks made prior to Shadowlands have been invalidated by the level squish, but new changes have made playing a twink more fun then ever.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shadowlands has brought major changes to the concept of Twinking. While many twinks that existed prior to Shadowlands have been invalidated by the level squish, the new changes have made playing a twink more fun then ever. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a World of Warcraft Twink</h2>



<p>The concept of a twink in World of Warcraft has been around since Vanilla. The basic idea is to keep a character low level and get the best gear possible for them. This makes the twink character considerably stronger than other characters of their level. This power discrepancy can be used to gain huge advantages in PvP battlegrounds or other organized content. It also allows the low level twink character to do things that high level characters cannot, normally due to scaling.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How to Disable Experience</h3>



<p>Since a twink tries to maximize their gear at a specific level, gaining experience is an issue. To turn off your experience on a character, talk with<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.wowhead.com/npc=35365/behsten">Behsten </a>in Stormwind for Alliance or <a href="https://www.wowhead.com/npc=35364/slahtz">Slahtz</a> in Orgrimmar for the Horde <em>(Behsten Slahtz &#8211; Best in Slots)</em>. This process will cost 10g. </p>



<p>Turning off experience will also debuff allies that you join a group with, reducing the amount of experience they earn. This debuff does not apply to allies that you are randomly matched with in the group finder.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shadowlands Twinking</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Level 1</h3>



<p>A level 1 twink can do some crazy stuff. However, outside of memes, their usefulness is limited. The biggest issue is that they cannot use the group finder tool to join dungeons or battlegrounds. Level 1 character cannot choose a specialization, giving them a very small pool of abilities to use. Also remember that Demon Hunter, Death Knights, and allied races do not start at level 1. </p>



<p>The most common build I&#8217;ve seen for a level 1 twink is maxing out a rogue&#8217;s agility stat, raising their dodge chance to above 100%. This causes every physical attack made against them miss, making them invincible to characters without magic damage. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Level 10</h3>



<p>Level 10 twinks are the most interesting to me. I made a few new characters in the Shadowlands prepatch and immediately noticed how effective they were with just heirlooms in dungeons. This effectiveness died off quickly though as they went up in level. </p>



<p>Level 10 twinks are a great choice to start with twinking. At level 10, you gain access to the dungeon finder and many dungeons thanks to Chromie. You also have access to non-epic battlegrounds, letting you match up with other players in PvP. You even get a mount, though it&#8217;s only the 60% ground version&#8230;</p>



<p>Allied races, Death Knights, and Demon Hunters start at level 10 lowering the amount of effort needed to start twinking. Level 10 characters get access to Chromie Time, allowing them to get gear from every old expansion.</p>



<p>At level 10, you will not have access to many abilities, making the class feel a bit boring. If you plan on making a level 10 twink, be sure to look at what abilities you will have access to when choosing a class. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Level 30</h3>



<p>Level 30 is another great consideration for a twink. You will have greater access to your classes abilities and talents, making many classes more fun to play. Importantly, many dungeons and other content open up at level 30, increasing the number of items you can equip.  You also get your 100% ground mount and a 150% flying mount. </p>



<p>It will take more work to get a level 30 character than a level 10 or 1, but the payoff can be great. If you get a group of like minded people together, you can run most of the old raids, scaled to level 30. With so many raids across so many expansions, the amount of content you have access to will keep you busy for a long time.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gearing Your Shadowlands Twink</h2>



<p>Shadowlands is still new, and new sources of gear are being discovered every day. I am currently working on my level 10 twinks and don&#8217;t have as much insight into level 1 or level 30.  I will update this list as I find more good sources of gear. <strong>Let me know what I&#8217;ve missed and I&#8217;ll add it to the list! </strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Raid Gear</h3>



<p>If you can get a friend to run you through the old raids, there is plenty of great gear for your twink character. Unfortunately, gear that drops from raids has a minimum level to even be able to equip it. If you are gearing something higher than a level 10 twink, there might be some good options in old raids. Consult the dungeon journal for the list of loot.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table aligncenter"><table><thead><tr><th>Expansion</th><th>Minimum <br>Level</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Classic</td><td>25</td></tr><tr><td>Burning Crusade</td><td>27</td></tr><tr><td>Wrath of the Lich King</td><td>30</td></tr><tr><td>Cataclysm</td><td>32</td></tr><tr><td>Mists of Pandaria</td><td>35</td></tr><tr><td>Warlords of Draenor</td><td>40</td></tr><tr><td>Legion</td><td>45</td></tr><tr><td>Battle for Azeroth</td><td>50</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Legion Artifact Weapon</h3>



<p>At level 10, you can start Legion. You can skip the scenario by finishing the initial quest where you get buffs and duel and then going back to the quest giver. Once in Dalaran, you&#8217;ll soon get a quest to obtain your artifact weapon. While the artifact no longer has its artifact power bonuses, it starts at <strong>item level 20</strong> with a large amount of stats.</p>



<p>This is a great choice to get early, though you will likely eventually replace it. You can further upgrade it by slotting relics earned in Legion dungeons. Use the Dungeon Journal to filter the slots you need and queue up for those dungeons specifically. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Sockets</h3>



<p>Jewelcrafting has changed in almost every expansion as Blizzard has tried to balance it. Certain expansions, like Burning Crusade, have gear with many more sockets than other comparable gear. The great thing about sockets is that the gems do not scale down when inserted. </p>



<p>Sockets let you choose which stat you want to focus on. This is even more important in twinking because you will be raising your stats well above intended levels, further exacerbating the power level differences.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">PvP Gear</h3>



<p>PvP gear can be purchased with honor tokens. This gear is normally Epic quality, giving it a huge amount of stats. PvP gear also has a high chance of having sockets, further increasing its effectiveness. </p>



<p>The issue with this gear is that there is normally a level requirement attached to it, making unusable on certain twinks. Check out the vendors in Stormwind or Orgrimmar, along with the expansion specific vendors like Area 52, to see what gear they have available for your level.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Trinkets</h3>



<p>Trinkets have the highest chance of any gear slot for not scaling correctly. With access to every expansion through Chromie Time, the number of trinkets you can pick from is extensive. Use the Dungeon Journal, filtered for trinkets, and look for trinkets that offer flat, non-scaled, bonuses.</p>



<p>Some of these unscaled trinkets will likely be nerfed. However, Blizzard has shown that it has trouble even fixing balance issues in current content, so fixing old trinkets will likely be low on their to-do list. Trinkets can potentially be a huge percentage of your overall damage.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Class Makes the Best Twink</h2>



<p>Class choice is mostly up to what you want to play. That said, some classes and specs will certainly outperform others since the game is not balanced with twinking in mind. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Arcane Mage Twink</h3>



<p>Arcane mage is my current personal favorite. This spec is actually what encouraged me to look into twinking. Even with just heirloom gear I was doing &gt;50% of my team&#8217;s damage and making holding aggro nearly impossible for the tank.</p>



<p>Arcane mage ramps its damage up by gaining arcane charges. These charges increase damage, but also increase mana cost. However, at level 10, you gain mana back very quickly, letting you stay at max stacks for pretty much the entire fight, even against bosses. In between pulls, you generally regain your mana back and are ready for the next group.  </p>



<p>While in single target fights you will be hard casting Arcane Blast, in most scenarios, the most effective rotation is to just spam Arcane Explosion. Since Arcane Explosion is an instant cast ability, you can spam it on the run and never need to stop. gather up enemies and they will fall quickly to your big purple blasts. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><a href="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/shadowlands-twink-arcane-mage.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/shadowlands-twink-arcane-mage.jpg" alt="Arcane Explosion" class="wp-image-1370"/></a></figure></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Blood Death Knight Twink</h3>



<p>Even non-twink Blood Death Knights can do some incredible solo content. The twink version even further augments their self sustain and AoE damage. They also wear plate armor, letting them equip any armor type in the game. This further increases the options you have for gearing them.</p>



<p>Blood Death Knights are a great choice if you are looking to solo content. You will be your own healer, easily topping off the small amount of damage you&#8217;ll be taking. You can also join group finder dungeons as the tank and not have the aggro issues that DPS twinks have. </p>



<p>Like high level Death Knights, they feel slow compared to other classes. You can get gear and buffs that increase your movement speed to offset this downside, but it will be at the expense of damage or defenses. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://https://marvweb.github.io/shadowlands-twink/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Win the Brewfest Chowdown</title>
		<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/brewfest-chowdown/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 20:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learn the best way to win the Brewfest Chowdown during Brewfest in World of Warcraft and earn your Brewfest Chowdown Trophy toy.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During the Brewfest holiday, you can earn a Toy called the <a href="https://www.wowhead.com/item=169865/brewfest-chowdown-trophy">Brewfest Chowdown Trophy</a> by winning the Brewfest Chowdown competition five times. This competition will pit you against three other players, so you&#8217;ll need a sound strategy to pull ahead.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Participate in the Brewfest Chowdown</h2>



<p>You&#8217;ll find Etga, the Chowdown Organizer, outside of Orgrimmar in the Brewfest area during the Brewfest holiday. If you haven&#8217;t completed it already, she&#8217;ll have a quest for participating in the competition.</p>



<p>To join, you&#8217;ll need to wait for the current competition to finish. When you are close you can see the current progress of the current players. As soon as one player reaches 10, the current competition is over and a new one opens up. Quickly right click on an empty seat to join. Be sure to wait for the competition to be over before sitting down, as people will get up from their seats near the end prior to completion to avoid the debuff.  </p>



<p>You will need a player in each seat (for a total of four) to start the competition.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><a href="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brewfest-chowdown-competition.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brewfest-chowdown-competition-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1056"/></a></figure></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Abilities</h2>



<p>Once you sit down at a seat, you&#8217;ll have access to three Brewfest Chowdown abilities: </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Eat Sausage</h3>



<p>The first ability eats one of the sausages on your current plate. The number of sausages remaining on your current plate can be seen in front of your character. Eating a sausage increases you Choke meter. When you Choke meter reach maximum, your character will be stunned and not able to use any abilities for a few seconds. A single sausage will add a random amount of Choke meter, usually between 20 and 30 points. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Refreshing Brew</h3>



<p>The second ability will remove some of your Choke meter. It has a maximum of three charges. Because of this charge system, as long as you keep it under three charges it will come off cooldown constantly. The amount of Choke meter removed can be greater than one sausage&#8217;s worth, so don&#8217;t drink unless your Choke meter is above about 50 or so. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">New Plate</h3>



<p>The third ability will create a new plate and increment your count. Even if you have eaten all your current plate, it will not count until you get a new one. You can see how many sausages are left on your current plate by looking at it in front of your character. Once you finish a plate, you wont be able to use the first ability until you get a new one. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Win the Brewfest Chowdown</h2>



<p>The number of sausages you receive per plate is random, so victory will often come down to a bit of RNG. That said however, you can maximize your chances by employing these strategies.</p>



<p>To start, eat two sausages and then take a drink of Refreshing Brew. From there, your goal is to <strong>keep your charges of Refreshing Brew below three</strong>. Keep eating sausages until you current plate is empty, even if this fills your choke meter. </p>



<p>While choking you will be stunned, but will <strong>still be refreshing the cooldown</strong> on Refreshing Brew and decreasing you choke meter by the normal amount. Also, if your choke meter is almost maxed, a sausage will only add up to the maximum 100, <strong>discarding any number over 100</strong>. </p>



<p>Watch your plate or the third ability closely, as this is where you will lose most of your time. Pressing <strong>New Plate as soon as possible</strong> can be the difference between wining and losing.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><a href="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brewfest-chowdown-trophy.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brewfest-chowdown-trophy-838x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1059"/></a><figcaption><em>The Brewfest Chowdown Trophy Toy</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p><em>To simplify by priority: </em></p>



<ol><li>Keep Refreshing Brew under three charges while not wasting it on Choke under 50</li><li>Get a New Plate when out of sausages</li><li>Spam Eat Sausage even if it means choking</li></ol>



<p>If it looks like you are not going to win, you can press the leave vehicle button or use the Exit ability to <strong>avoid getting the debuff </strong>that stops you from participating again immediately. You can also kill yourself by falling to remove the debuff; the graveyard is very close.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
