<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kingdom Hearts &#8211; MarvWeb</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/games/kingdom-hearts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 20:58:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Theory: Pluto is the Master of Masters</title>
		<link>/pluto-is-the-master-of-masters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 18:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=2142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are too many oddities surrounding Pluto for them to be merely coincidence. There are too many scenes where Pluto is acting out of the norm for him to just be Mickey's loyal pet.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>SPOILERS AHEAD &#8211; I WILL BE PULLING FACTS FROM MANY KINGDOM HEARTS GAMES</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>ONLY READ ON IF YOU ARE CAUGHT UP WITH THE STORY UP UNTIL THE END OF KH3</em></p>



<p>With the announcement of Kingdom Hearts IV, I wanted to put one of my Kingdom Hearts theories out there. In this post I&#8217;ll share with you all the hints that have been there all along that lead me to this conclusion. If it ends up being true, I can say that I called it and point to this post as proof!</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the theory: <strong>the Master of Masters has disguised himself as King Mickey&#8217;s dog Pluto</strong>.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who is the Master of Masters (MoM)</h2>



<p>There is a lot of extra lore for the Kingdom Hearts universe, so I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised to hear that you don&#8217;t even know who the Master of Masters is. The MoM has really only been explored in the mobile game Kingdom Hearts <em>χ</em> (Chi, like the Chi blade from KH3). He is the first known Keyblade Master, with no known master that taught him. He trained some of the first Keyblade Masters we know of in history who went on to train other Masters, making him the Master of Masters.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX.webp"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="300" height="731" src="/wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-9401" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/The_Master_of_Masters_KHX-123x300.webp 123w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The MoM as he appeared in KHχ</figcaption></figure>



<p>He claims that he can see into the future using his Gazing Eye, which he uses to make predictions or possibly see how his choices play out. The eye is part of a Keyblade that the MoM passes down to his apprentice. The Keyblade is said to have no name by the MoM, but considering it contains the Gazing Eye, many know it now as the Gazing Eye Keyblade. This is the Keyblade we see old Xehanort wield.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort.png"><img decoding="async" width="653" height="490" src="/wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9344" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort.png 653w, /wp-content/uploads/Sora-vs-Xehanort-300x225.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 653px) 100vw, 653px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Xehanort wielding the Gazing Eye Keyblade</figcaption></figure>



<p>The MoM decided to pass some of this knowledge of the future on to five Keyblade masters he dubbed the Foretellers, telling each to build a group of Keyblade wielders and tasking each group with specific goals. He gave each of them a Book of Prophecies to help them with their goal, presumably written using the insight he gained from the Gazing Eye. However, he created one of these books for each of them and told them not to share the contents with anyone, even their fellow Foretellers. It&#8217;s likely that each book was different, and specifically written to influence events as he had planned or foresaw.</p>



<p>As shown in Kingdom Hearts χ Back Cover (worth a watch if you haven&#8217;t seen it), the MoM has foreseen the Keyblade war and predicts that &#8220;Darkness will prevail and the light will expire.&#8221; He believes the war to be inevitable, so his main goal is to take care of what happens afterwards, implying that he wants to shape events so that they happen the way he wants them to.</p>



<p>Prior to tasking the Foretellers with their roles, the MoM handed one other task to his apprentice Luxu. He gave Luxu the Gazing Eye Keyblade to watch everything that was going to transpire from afar. He told Luxu to train an apprentice of his own and bequeath him the Gazing Eye Keyblade. This would presumably allow him to view the events of the future, and help him craft his Book(s) of Prophecy just right as to shape the outcome. He also gave Luxu a large black box, of which the contents are currently unknown, that he was to keep safe. As of KH3, Maleficent seems to be trying to find this box for unknown reasons.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum.png"><img decoding="async" width="751" height="557" src="/wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9084" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum.png 751w, /wp-content/uploads/gazing-eye-scala-ad-caelum-300x223.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 751px) 100vw, 751px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Gazing Eye Keyblade hanging in Scala Ad Caelum</figcaption></figure>



<p>How does this all tie in to the mainline Kingdom Hearts games? Well now that the Dark Seeker (Xehanort) saga is complete, the next saga has been dubbed the &#8220;Lost Masters&#8221; saga, almost certainly referencing the Master of Master&#8217;s storyline. This prediction is almost fully confirmed by one of the ending scenes of KH3 that sees Xigbar, wielding the Gazing Eye Keyblade and standing over the black box, summon back four of the five Foretellers and reveal himself to be Luxu. He announces that the role the MoM gave him is finally complete.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="586" src="/wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-1024x586.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8207" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-1024x586.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-300x172.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-768x440.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu-1536x879.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/xigbar-is-luxu.jpg 1682w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Xigbar reveals himself to be Luxu</figcaption></figure>



<p>There&#8217;s a lot of lore I&#8217;m skipping over here that involves the MoM, but that should be sufficient for the purposes of this theory. On to Pluto!</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Every Scene with Pluto in the Kingdom Hearts Series</h2>



<p>I found a video by the YouTube channel OzBroGamerz that contains every scene I&#8217;m about to talk about . You can check it out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zEOGzqq12aU&amp;ab_channel=OzBroGamerz">here</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts &#8211; King Mickey Goes Missing</h3>



<p>The first scene we see Pluto in has him waiting patiently behind King Mickey&#8217;s throne for someone to discover that Mickey has run off. He is holding a letter presumably written by Mickey that informs Donald that Mickey has gone off to investigate why the stars have been going out. While the letter is being shown to us on screen, we see Pluto sleeping peacefully in his bed. The contents of the letter are as follows:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Donald,<br>Sorry to rush off without sayin&#8217; goodbye, but there&#8217;s big trouble brewin&#8217;.<br>Not sure why, but the stars have been blinkin&#8217; out, one by one. And that means disaster can&#8217;t be far behind. I hate to leave you all but I&#8217;ve gotta go check into it.<br>There&#8217;s someone with a &#8220;Key&#8221;—the Key to our survival. So I need you and Goofy to find him, and stick with him. Got it?<br>We need that key or we&#8217;re doomed! So go to Traverse Town and find Leon. He&#8217;ll point you in the right direction.<br>P.S. Would ya apologize to Minnie for me? Thanks, pal.<br>Signed &#8211; Mickey</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="689" height="449" src="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9294" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1.png 689w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Napping-1-300x196.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 689px) 100vw, 689px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto is shown while the letter is read</figcaption></figure>



<p>Take a second and reread the letter, but pretend it is instead the MoM that has written it, not Mickey. This letter makes so much more sense if it was written by someone who could see into the future. It is vague on details, but very specific on instructions. </p>



<p>First off, why is this letter addressed specifically to Donald? Why not Goofy? How did Mickey know that Pluto would deliver this letter specifically to Donald? Also, why is it written this way? Look at Mickey&#8217;s letter written at the end of Re: Coded. His letter (that we see him writing) uses much more formal language. You could argue that Mickey wrote this letter much more whimsically because it was addressed to Donald. However, would Mickey rush off and leave his home in such a hurry for something that was just &#8220;big trouble brewin&#8217;.&#8221; To me, this letter sound more like someone pretending to be Mickey by mirroring his speech, but not his writing style.</p>



<p>Second, why not tell Donald in person? It&#8217;s not like this matter of noticing &#8220;stars blinking out&#8221; was so pressing that he couldn&#8217;t talk to his friends first. Was Mickey concerned that Donald would try to stop him? As the King, I think he can do as he pleases. Was he concerned that Donald and Goofy would want to come with him? If he was concerned for their safety, why would he send them to find the Keyblade? </p>



<p>At the end of this opening scene, we see Pluto leap into the Gummy Ship, joining Donald and Goofy on their adventure.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pluto in Traverse Town</h3>



<p>We see Pluto walking with Donald and Goofy in the opening, but Pluto quickly wanders off from the group, stumbling upon Sora passed out. He licks him awake, and then forcefully hits Sora to snap him out of his daze. When Sora asks Pluto if he knows where they are, Pluto excitedly runs off leading Sora to Leon and the others. After this, we don&#8217;t see Pluto until the very end of the first game.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="695" height="551" src="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9292" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora.png 695w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-Hitting-Sora-300x238.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 695px) 100vw, 695px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto hitting Sora</figcaption></figure>



<p>This scene is described in later games as the start of Sora&#8217;s journey. And who was there to get him started? Pluto. Pluto licking Sora is uninteresting enough, but aggressively hitting him with his paws shortly after because Sora believes himself to still be dreaming? Really, <a href="https://youtu.be/zEOGzqq12aU?t=451">watch the scene yourself,</a> it&#8217;s oddly aggressive and intentional for a dog. Once Sora is up and about and asking questions, Pluto runs off. His role complete, we don&#8217;t see Pluto again until the end of the game. Where does he go?</p>



<p>When Sora, Donald, and Goofy eventually run into Leon, Yuffie, and Aerith, they don&#8217;t seem to know exactly what is going on either, despite the recommendation from &#8220;Mickey.&#8221; They know that Heartless are attracted to the Keyblade and not much else. It sounds like they got a similar vague letter that was light on details and heavy on instruction.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts Ending</h3>



<p>At the end of Kingdom Hearts 1, we see Pluto one last time. Sora, Donald, and Goofy are walking through a field discussing what they should do next. As the three of them realize they don&#8217;t have much to go on, Pluto saunters across their path holding a letter with the King&#8217;s seal in his mouth. Rather than give them the letter, Pluto runs off, getting the crew to chase him. The camera pulls away, and the game ends with the final, non voice acted line &#8220;Remember Sora, you are the one who will open the door to the light.&#8221; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="855" height="471" src="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9298" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter.png 855w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter-300x165.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/Pluto-With-Letter-768x423.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 855px) 100vw, 855px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">What a coincidence</figcaption></figure>



<p>This is the first scene that really made me question Pluto. You may write this off as the devs having a bit of fun, hinting nonspecifically at more adventures to come in a game they weren&#8217;t certain they&#8217;d continue, but this is too odd when taken as explicit canon. Why would Pluto not give them the letter? How did he happen to show up EXACTLY when the crew was without purpose?</p>



<p>This field is not in Traverse Town (at least as far as I can tell), so Pluto somehow got to a different world. Lore wise we know that this should only be possible using Corridors of Darkness or a ship like the Gummi Ship. So how would Pluto have made it to another world? When did he meet up with Mickey to get this letter? Scene from KH2 and Coded show other times Pluto has used Corridors of Darkness. </p>



<p>The final quote is similar to the other detached non voice acted lines we hear throughout the game. It seems <a href="https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/boards/943347-kingdom-hearts-birth-by-sleep/57971099">Nomura has confirmed</a> that the voice we hear in the beginning is actually Mickey, but he is very specific by saying Mickey is speaking to Sora&#8217;s heart when he acquires the Keyblade and just before passing through the last door of the End of the World. So who is speaking here? It would make sense for the MoM to know that Sora was destined to open the Door of Light in KH2.</p>



<p>Finally, if you look at Pluto after the team start running after him, he doesn&#8217;t even have the letter in his mouth anymore. An oversight by the devs? Perhaps. Or perhaps the letter was just a fake made to get Sora and the others to chase him toward the next place he needed them to be.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts: Chain of Memories &#8211; Castle Oblivion</h3>



<p>Chain of Memories opens right where KH1 left off, showing the second half of the final scene with the team running after Pluto. We see that the team has given up the chase of Pluto, and are sleeping for the night. Someone in a signature Black Cloak (very likely Marluxia) appears to Sora and tells him that &#8220;Ahead lies something you need.&#8221; Sora then finds himself outside of Castle Oblivion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="590" src="/wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-1024x590.png" alt="" class="wp-image-8966" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-1024x590.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-300x173.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion-768x442.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/Castle-Oblivion.png 1106w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto led them straight to Marluxia</figcaption></figure>



<p>Perhaps you could say that Marluxia could have abducted Sora from anywhere and taken him to Castle Oblivion; perhaps the spot Pluto led them to was irrelevant for Marluxia&#8217;s plot. But once again, it&#8217;s all too odd to be overlooked. We see Pluto give the letter to Donald at the start of KH1, but this time he runs away from the team, refusing to give them the letter. Pluto even manages to lose them completely, right before Marluxia shows up and CoM starts.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fighting Alone Isn&#8217;t Easy</h3>



<p>As Sora makes his way through Castle Oblivion, he comes to the conclusion that &#8220;fighting alone isn&#8217;t as easy as [he] thought.&#8221; Two cards (Sora&#8217;s memories) float down behind him and manifest into Donald and Goofy in a big display of light and sound. After a quick conversation, the three discover that Pluto is sitting silently behind Sora. Donald questions what he&#8217;s doing here, but Goofy reassures him it makes sense since they all came to Traverse Town together. Jiminy consults the journal and reminds everyone that Pluto left Donald and Goofy before they met up with Sora. We don&#8217;t see Pluto any more in CoM.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="852" height="573" src="/wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9460" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here.png 852w, /wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here-300x202.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/whats-pluto-doing-here-768x517.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 852px) 100vw, 852px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Good question Donald, what IS Pluto doing here?</figcaption></figure>



<p>Ok, the lore for Chain of Memories was tough, but my understanding is that everything inside Castle Oblivion was Sora&#8217;s memories. This scene explicitly shows Sora creating memories of Donald and Goofy to help him, manifesting them from cards. So then why was Pluto here with them? If Sora had JUST gotten to the memories of his best friends, why would he have already manifested Pluto? We didn&#8217;t see or hear Pluto appear, so he must have already been around. The crew are even explicitly confused as to why Pluto is here, but get distracted by the rest of the odd happenings and don&#8217;t speak any more about it.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s more likely that this Pluto is actually not a memory, but the real Pluto who has also entered Castle Oblivion to watch and monitor what transpires. Everything goes to plan, so the MoM doesn&#8217;t have to interfere further in this game.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kingdom Hearts II &#8211; Pluto and the Corridor of Darkness</h3>



<p>We see Pluto in The World That Never Was chasing after Axel as he walks through a Corridor of Darkness. The Corridor closes behind him and Pluto is sad he missed it. He is happy though to discover that another Corridor has opened just behind him and quickly runs through. (In the original version of this scene, someone whistles to him, but not in Final Mix.)</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="606" height="802" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9291" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness.jpg 606w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-goes-into-darkness-227x300.jpg 227w" sizes="(max-width: 606px) 100vw, 606px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto delves into the darkness</figcaption></figure>



<p>Ok, if you haven&#8217;t agreed with any of my points so far, you have to at least admit this is a weird scene. First off, why is Pluto in The World That Never Was, the home base of Organization XIII. How is he surviving in a world full of Heartless and Nobodies? How can Pluto survive the corridors when everyone else that uses them has to wear a protective cloak?</p>



<p>The scenes that follow hint that Riku is opening these portals for Pluto. However, this is not the only time Pluto enters corridors. Are multiple members of Organization XIII using Pluto? In truth, we don&#8217;t know who is teleporting Pluto around or why.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pluto to the Rescue</h3>



<p>Axel arrives to capture Kairi. Before she can agree to go with him, Pluto arrives and seems to warn her of Axel. A whistle is heard and another Corridor of Darkness appears. Pluto aggressively encourages Kairi to go through the corridor with him. They appear in some place with floating Nobody symbols all around before another whistle spawns a corridor before them. This corridor however is not dark like we&#8217;ve come to know, but light. Kairi sees a masked figure before the corridor closes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1003" height="947" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9295" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi.jpg 1003w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi-300x283.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-saves-kairi-768x725.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A corridor of light?</figcaption></figure>



<p>I think this is the only corridor we see that looks like this. The only other thing I can think of that resembles this is the Door to Light that Sora and Riku use to escape the Realm of Darkness.  But perhaps it&#8217;s just that every Corridor of Darkness takes them to this transit hub, but from this side, connecting back to a world looks like a Corridor of Light.</p>



<p>Talking about Pluto specifically though, even if you believe that all of these portal were just Riku&#8217;s plan, Pluto seems to know exactly what to do. No fear or hesitation, it&#8217;s almost like he knows what should be happening and is happy to keep things on track.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pluto and Kairi Captured</h3>



<p>Once Sora catches up with Roxas&#8217;s friends in Twilight Town, they tell him about how Kairi stayed with them for a while. In the flashback, we see Pluto is there too. Axel finds them and takes Kairi. Pluto follows them through the corridor. </p>



<p>In the next scene we see that Pluto and Kairi are locked up in the Castle That Never Was. Pluto comforts Kairi until Namine appears in another Corridor of Darkness, telling Kairi to come with her. Saix appear to block their path, but is soon driven off by Riku. As Saix is escaping, Riku plans to follow him. Kairi calls out for him to wait, but he doesn&#8217;t turn away from the corridor until Pluto runs up to him barking, getting between him and the portal. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="832" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-1024x832.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-9297" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-1024x832.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-300x244.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku-768x624.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-stopping-riku.jpg 1104w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto convinces Riku when Kairi could not</figcaption></figure>



<p>Many took this scene as Pluto happy to see Riku since he&#8217;s been helping him through this Kairi plot, but if you watch the scene, Pluto clearly tries to stop Riku from pursuing Saix. This gives Riku a chance to talk with Kairi, potentially putting him back of the path to redemption he is destined for.</p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Re: Coded Retcon</h3>



<p>Re: Coded gives us one new scene involving Pluto. During the all-hands-in forming of the Sora-Donald-Goofy alliance, we see Pluto in the distance sniffing the ground. A corridor of Darkness appears before him and Pluto runs through. Back in Mickey&#8217;s Castle, real Donald asks why that showed up at all, and Jiminy comments that he certainly didn&#8217;t write that.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="552" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-1024x552.png" alt="" class="wp-image-9296" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-1024x552.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-300x162.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off-768x414.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/pluto-sneaks-off.png 1201w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pluto sneaks off</figcaption></figure>



<p>Perhaps it is just the devs adding a scene to answer the question as to how Pluto got around in the first few games. However, even if you take that as true, who opened the corridor for Pluto this time? It wouldn&#8217;t have been Riku yet. And again, how is Pluto able to use these corridors so often with no protection?</p>



<p>Similar to Chain of Memories, my understanding of Coded is a bit weak. I believe that the journal that Mickey uses is just the one that Jiminy wrote, which happened to include some extra stuff Jiminy did not write. The insights gained from exploring the journal are used to help put Sora on his path in saving everyone in KH3. So who added this specific data about Pluto to the journal and why? Jiminy specifically calls out that he didn&#8217;t write this. While the other games have been rather covert with their Pluto hints, this game wants you to notice Pluto and the oddity surrounding him.</p>



<p>It seems most people believe the person who added to the journal was Namine, or data-Namine. But Malificent specificaly comments about he Book of Prophecies in Coded, even hinting that Jiminy&#8217;s journal may be somehow tied to it. She says that the Book of Prophecies can create worlds, much like the Datascape and the plot of Coded. Also, the rhyming scheme of this quote added to Jiminy&#8217;s journal reminds me of the two quotes from the Book of Prophecies we have heard:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Their hurting will be mended when you return to end it.</p>
<cite><strong>Page added to Jiminy&#8217;s Journal</strong></cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>On that fated land, a great war shall transpire. Darkness will prevail and the light expire.</p>
<cite><strong>Book of Prophecies Final Entry</strong></cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>Imbalance observed, strength misplaced, a future filled with sorrow.</em></p>



<p><em>Words of truth misunderstood as they explore the secret of tomorrow.</em></p>



<p><em>With a single strike, toll the bells and herald the end, bringing war upon us, as fate did intend.</em></p>
<cite><strong>Book of Prophecies Lost Page</strong></cite></blockquote>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"> Putting It All Together</h3>



<p>There are too many oddities surrounding Pluto for them to be merely coincidence. There are too many scenes where Pluto is acting out of the norm for him to just be Mickey&#8217;s loyal pet. And is it not fitting too that the MoM would turn himself into a dog? From the little we know of the MoM&#8217;s personality, playing a dog would be a perfect role for him. </p>



<p>I can easily imagine him telling us during the reveal that he&#8217;s been there the whole time, making sure everyone stayed on track. Flashbacks to many of these scenes will play to show the player all the hints that were there. Everyone will be shocked and surprised, but not us!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/pluto.webp"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="232" height="299" src="/wp-content/uploads/pluto.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-9290"/></a></figure>



<p>The Master of Masters has been with us since the beginning, hiding his identity. <strong>Pluto is the Master of Masters.</strong></p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
