<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Opinions &#8211; MarvWeb</title>
	<atom:link href="https://https://marvweb.github.io/category/opinions/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 08:44:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Return to Unchallengeable News Media &#8211; GME, Fake News, &#038; Influencers</title>
		<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/unchallengeable-news-media-gme-fake-news-influencers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 08:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As news reporting evolves at an alarming pace, GME and "Glacier Capital" offer us an interesting insight into the state of news media.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Case of Glacier Capital</h2>



<p>If you have been following the GME saga, there has been a lot of questionable news thrown around. News meant to dissuade purchasing, news meant to encourage buying, an everything in-between. Even news that attempts to just present facts has some level of implicit bias.</p>



<p>Recently, there was talk on the crowd sourced news site Reddit of a company called Glacier Capital opening a new short position in GME. This news quickly spread because of the nature of crowd sourced news; people attempting to earn a small amount of fame and fake internet points quickly jumped on the train, trying to get their posts about the news they had heard out there ASAP. Here are a couple examples:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Superstonk/comments/netvg0/i_read_glacier_capitals_q1_2021_letter_to/">I Read Glacier Capital&#8217;s Q1 2021 Letter To Investors</a></li><li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Superstonk/comments/nerh2y/opening_a_167_short_position_headass_ol_i_love/">Glacier Capital, the price is wrong</a></li></ul>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/glacier-capital-meme.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1775"/><figcaption>a</figcaption></figure></div>



<p><strong>However, in less than a day, Reddit has a new stance on Glacier Capital: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Glacier Capital doesn&#8217;t exist.</em> </p>



<p>At least not to the extent that was originally implied. It exists on paper and has a website, but no one can find any actual information on a &#8220;real&#8221; company of this name. If you look up their listed business address, it looks like someone&#8217;s apartment. This is further backed up by the fact that their announcement of shorting GME was followed by a very long explanation of why they felt GME would go down in value.</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Superstonk/comments/nezcn1/glacier_capital_does_not_exist/">&#8220;Glacier Capital&#8221; does not exist</a></li><li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Superstonk/comments/new7b6/check_out_glacier_capitals_head_office_no/">Check out Glacier Capital’s head office. No, seriously&#8230;</a></li></ul>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/glacier-capital-address.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1776"/></figure></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crowd Sourced News &#8211; Working Together to Find the Truth</h2>



<p>Think what you will about who is right and who is wrong here, but I found this to be an interesting insight into the state of news media. </p>



<p>It is tough to trust main stream media because many feel they purposefully lie to push an agenda or that they have been bought out. The idea of &#8220;fake news&#8221; has been thrown around a lot lately, claiming major news sources are purposefully adding bias and reporting news in specific ways to tell the tale they want to, rather than simply presenting facts.</p>



<p>However, it is also difficult to trust crowd sourced media (like Reddit) because they are not journalists. They will often jump on the hype train for fake internet points and not do enough research to verify their claims. On top of that, like a game of &#8220;telephone,&#8221; even if the news was correct to begin with, the truth can get lost as it is retold by more and more people looking to get in on the hype.</p>



<p>There is an interesting  difference that has been demonstrated by this Glacier Capital story between conventional news media and crowd sourced news media. Crowd sourced news eventually corrected itself. As time progresses, crowd sourced news can become more trustworthy. It has had time to be challenged, and those challenges are more difficult to suppress. In contrast, a conventional news source that was purposeful lying would never expose its own lie.</p>



<p>The crux here is that crowd sourced news can be readily challenged. This is why people are moving away from news outlets that simply tell you the news with no real avenue for challenge. We are moving instead toward news sources we can actively engage in. As long as we have a healthy discourse, the truth will eventually rise to the top (assuming we have good faith actors involved). </p>



<p><strong>But what if we lose that readily challengeable discourse?</strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Influencers &#8211; A Return to Unchallengeable News</h2>



<p>&#8220;Influencers&#8221; are a quickly rising trend in the connected world. As people lose faith in traditional media, we often end up replacing our news source with influencers: people who&#8217;s opinion is respected in a group or community. Influencers can be a single person or even a group of people who generally speak for a community.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stock-influencer.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stock-influencer-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1779" width="512" height="342"/></a></figure></div>



<p>We may not intentionally seek out news from an influencer, but if you resign yourself from other news sources you will hear about extraordinary news eventually, and it will often be through the people/places you spend time with/at.</p>



<p>Influencers generally want to be on the cutting edge of breaking news in their specific area of interest. Knowing information that others do not is a great way to become, or remain, influential. However, this will often encourage influencers (or aspiring influencers) to announce news before they have had sufficient time to investigate and verify information. </p>



<p>Influencers also generally want to be controversial in an attempt to be more &#8220;interesting&#8221; and &#8220;clickable&#8221; than their competition. Prioritizing controversy means they are more likely to have extreme takes. </p>



<p>Finally, people are also much more likely to follow influencers who&#8217;s opinions they already agree with, leading to an increase in bias. The groups that form around an influencer often have at least a few things in common. Those similarities often end up being what defines the community.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Communities, Tribes, and Echo Chambers &#8211; A Further Division of an Already Divided World</h2>



<p>As people start to distrust main stream media more and more, influencers will grow more&#8230; <em>influential</em>. With the eventuality of influencers as a major source of information (a reality we may already be living in), we&#8217;ll be more exposed to biased, extreme &#8220;takes&#8221; on breaking news that we don&#8217;t have all of the information for. This will lead to people forming exaggerated opinions early, making them less likely to consider dissenting opinions. </p>



<p>We already see this with echo chambers: people join groups of like minded people and disregarding anything the contradicts what they want to believe. I see it with myself too: I am very unlikely to believe anything that certain news outlets say, even if there is no particular reason to distrust their reporting of that specific news story. I chose to disregard these &#8220;untrustworthy&#8221; news sources. My personal list of untrustworthy news has grown steadily over the years. </p>



<p>Anecdotally, I&#8217;ve gotten my news about GME pretty much solely from Reddit. I believe there is too much of a profit motive in the case of GME for less challengeable news sources. Unfortunately, crowd sourced news has a huge potential to become an echo chamber. People who deviate from the consensus get voted into obscurity and news that agrees with the masses rises to prominence.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Next Iteration of News &#8211; Influencers</h2>



<p>The flaws of main stream news and crowd sourced news will continue to push people toward influencer based news. The issue here is that influencer news is the worst of both worlds.</p>



<p>Influencers will often present non-factual data as truth, purposefully or accidentally. They are susceptible to being bought out or purposefully pushing an agenda like main stream news. They also have a high potential to report non-factual news unintentionally, like crowd sourced news, because they are rushing to be timely and interesting. </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<p>Influencers are often not reporters, and have none of the constraints of being a dedicated source of news like a business would. They are free to present their takes on developing stories as their opinion and often face little to no consequence for misreporting news.</p>



<p>Influencers also are not subject to the automatic fact checking and correction found in crowd sourced news. It is easy for an influencer to dismiss and suppress the opinions of less influential people in their community, as by definition they are &#8220;influential.&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>This is the real issue: influencers are missing the checks that come with the other types of news.</strong> </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stock-newspaper.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stock-newspaper-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1781" width="512" height="384"/></a></figure></div>



<p>As we continue to divide into the tribes and communities we choose to associate ourselves with, we will stop hearing the dissenting opinions. We will end up surrounded by people we agree with and actively reject those who are not a part of our group.</p>



<p>This has likely been happening to some extent forever. However (and perhaps I&#8217;m being an alarmist), I feel like it is getting worse, quickly. The most difficult part for me is that I can&#8217;t see any way that it will get better. </p>



<p>At this point I feel like people have chosen their tribes, and anyone who tries to convince them to leave said tribe is just a member of the &#8220;other&#8221; tribe. As we vilify the other tribe, we widen the divide.</p>



<p><strong>At some point, the divide will be uncrossable.</strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torghast is Not Fun and Not Rewarding</title>
		<link>https://https://marvweb.github.io/torghast-is-not-fun-and-not-rewarding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 20:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World of Warcraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marvweb.com/?p=1526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now that we are a couple months into Shadowlands and the rush has settled down, issues with longevity start to become more obvious. While Torghast started as something fresh and exciting, I&#8217;m starting to struggle to find the motivation to even finish my weekly Soul Ash runs, let alone continue my slow grind through Twisting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Now that we are a couple months into Shadowlands and the rush has settled down, issues with longevity start to become more obvious. While Torghast started as something fresh and exciting, I&#8217;m starting to struggle to find the motivation to even finish my weekly Soul Ash runs, let alone continue my slow grind through Twisting Corridors. </p>



<p>Torghast isn&#8217;t fun. I found myself super excited to try out Torghast on my freshly capped 60s just so I could see what kind of nonsense I could get into with them. But now that I&#8217;ve played through it on multiple classes, I realize that the powers are boringly &#8220;balanced.&#8221; From what I saw of the beta, you used to be able to scale your character to ridiculous levels of power that easily led to some great &#8220;did you see that?&#8221; moments. The Torghast we have now however is no where near as exciting; it&#8217;s too balanced and boring. </p>



<p>Don&#8217;t misunderstand my use of <em>balance </em>here, I know that many classes/specs struggle while some classes excel. What I mean is that runs usually end up being pretty close to the same every time. Due to a lack of Anima power diversity and the relatively small impact most powers have, you end each run at pretty close to the same power level.</p>



<p>Torghast also doesn&#8217;t feel rewarding. Twisting Corridor&#8217;s cosmetic rewards are a good start, but it&#8217;s a one time thing, on one character. Once I finish, I don&#8217;t see myself ever going back into the Twisting Corridors. Even if my friends want help, the idea of another multi-hour run that could very well end in complete failure with nothing to show for it doesn&#8217;t sound fun to me. </p>



<p>Unfortunately fixing one of these problems, rewards or fun, will likely hurt the other. <strong>Is Torghast supposed to be a part of the endgame grind, or is it just for fun? </strong>Blizz needs to pick one, because this conflict is ruining Torghast.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Serious Game Mode &#8211; OR &#8211; Just For Fun</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A New Endgame Mode</h3>



<p>Torghast could be a whole new endgame mode, similar to Raids, PvP, and Mythic+. Adding more difficult content while balancing across classes/specs could make Torghast something people spend a majority of their game time playing. Imagine a Torghast where you actually chose to craft the Torghast +Phatasma legendary first, where you picked your covenant and soulbinds based on which one was best in Torghast. WoW has always lacked challenging single player content. The Mage Tower challenge back in Legion was a great example of a personal challenge. It seems that it was quite well received by the player base who had little to no outlet for challenging content that didn&#8217;t rely on at least one other person. Torghast can be a replayable, challenging, endgame, solo game mode alongside the group based endgame modes we already have.</p>



<p>However, with increased difficulty needs to come increased rewards. Every main game mode can currently stand on its own in regard to gearing. While you can augment your gear through the other main game modes, your character will increase in power by just doing that one type of content. That is currently not true in Torghast. To do well in Torghast, you need to get gear from elsewhere. If Torghast is to become a main game mode, the rewards need to be comparable to other modes. </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Fun Casual Experience</h3>



<p>WoW has continuously moved away from the idea of &#8220;just for fun&#8221; content with every new system introduced being required to keep your character at maximum efficiency. Torghast had the opportunity to be something that you do for fun, rather than because you feel like you are required to to remain relevant. Unfortunately, the fact that legendaries require you to complete many Torghast runs, it&#8217;s not &#8220;just for fun.&#8221; </p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had a few really fun experiences in Torghast that have stuck with me. During the first week of the Torghast event where you can pick and buff the dogs, I had the death explosion of my pet take more than half of the final boss&#8217;s health. My friend recently leveled up his Priest and was excited to show me a build he had gotten that allowed him to one shot the final boss with a single super-buffed Mind Blast. Getting a free Starfall when swapping into Moonkin along with a free Stampeding Roar from cat, when matched with the Stellar Drift talent, makes Balance druid exhilarating. There are some great opportunities for fun in Torghast, but they are the exception when they should be the norm. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://marvweb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dog-bomb.jpg" alt="Dog death deals more than half of the boss's health" class="wp-image-1529"/><figcaption>Dog death deals more than half of the boss&#8217;s health</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Torghast&#8217;s longevity would be so much better if these types of experiences happened more often. I guess the concern would be that one-shotting bosses is too easy, but isn&#8217;t the point of a game to have fun? Fun can be found in difficulty, yes. But if you are already having fun with the ridiculousness of the situation, difficulty isn&#8217;t really needed. There are plenty of other outlets for difficulty in WoW, but few modes that are just for fun. Another critisim of a just-for-fun Torghast would be that legendaries would be too easy to get. But, is that really an issue? If legendaries should be challenging to earn, why not take Soul Ash out of Torghast and have it only drop from Mythic Raids, Mythic+20s, or 2400+ rated PvP?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other Issues</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rewards For Failure</h3>



<p>I know that many people are against the idea of &#8220;everyone gets a trophy,&#8221; but there needs to be something to show for partial Torghast runs. Torghast&#8217;s binary reward nature of everything or nothing discourages challenging yourself with runs that you aren&#8217;t pretty much guaranteed to win. And if you already know you are going to win, then the run itself becomes superfluous.</p>



<p>Almost every successful Roguelite rewards you for failure. In Hades, for example, you aren&#8217;t expected to complete your first run. You lose, and when you do, you still gain power. That power makes slowly makes you stronger, and eventually you complete the challenge. You are always making progress, even in failure. Even in WoW, we get partial rewards in every other major game mode:</p>



<p><strong>Raids </strong>give loot for every boss killed, not just the final boss. The gear you get from partial completions week after week eventually get you and your raid group enough gear to conquer the boss you are stuck on. </p>



<p><strong>PvP </strong>gives honor for losses. Even if you are a fresh capped 60 without your trinket set bonus, you still get some currency after getting destroyed. Even going into Skirms and dying in the opener over and over gets you closer to better gear and a stronger character.</p>



<p><strong>Normal, Heroic, and Mythic-0 dungeons</strong> give loot per boss, not for completion. Though it doesn&#8217;t happen often, if your group is struggling to finish off a final boss of a dungeon, you at least got a chance at loot from the previous bosses you downed. </p>



<p><strong>Mythic+</strong> is probably the closest to the reward state of Torghast, but even in this elitist gamemode that spawned the concept of Raider.io to filter out bad players in an attempt to minimize wasted time with no rewards, you can still get a reward after you fail the timer. </p>



<p>With rewards offered at every floor boss, or even as a chance from every enemy killed, failure in Torghast will not be as disheartening. Knowing that wiping on a final boss in Twisting Corridors could leave me with nothing to show for the last 3 hours of work getting there is not something I enjoy.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">More Variety For More Replayability</h3>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Anima Powers</h4>



<p>While it was cool to see the powers on my first few playthroughs and fantasize about all the cool stuff I might be able to do, I now know pretty much all of the limited pool of powers each of my classes can get. After a few runs of Torghast, you&#8217;ve likely seen almost every power your specialization has. There need to be more choices to keep runs fresh. By the end of each run, most of my characters end at about the same power level. Especially in Twisted Corridors, where you have an increased chance of getting the rarer powers, you end up with pretty similar builds every run.</p>



<p>Also, many choices don&#8217;t even end up feeling like choices at all. Am I really going to pick &#8220;Mawrats don&#8217;t run away&#8221; over almost anything else? I&#8217;ve tried a full Mawrat build, and can tell you that once you get to the last boss, arguably the most important part of any run, the Mawrat build does not work well with no Mawrats&#8230; </p>



<p>WoW has this choice issue elsewhere too. Similar to talents, gear, spec, covenant, and rotation, there almost always ends up be a &#8220;best&#8221; choice. It makes sense to not make the meta choice if the non-meta choice is more fun, but if I&#8217;m choosing between something like &#8220;puts a DoT on enemies,&#8221; &#8220;attacks deal extra damage,&#8221; or &#8220;your health is increased,&#8221; none of these are engaging at all and the choice should always be which one is &#8220;best&#8221; since none of them are &#8220;fun.&#8221; </p>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Enemy and Environment Diversity</h4>



<p>Why are there so few types of enemies in Torghast? Lore wise, the Maw is currently where every mortal soul is going, so it would make sense for literally any group or faction that exists in WoW to exist here. And yet, all we get is the Jailer&#8217;s minions, Fae, Kvaldir, and Fire Elementals&#8230; Every wing ends up feeling so similar because there are so few enemy types. A diverse set of enemies would help to keep each run fresh, as certain powers could interact with certain abilities in interesting ways.</p>



<p>One of the coolest things about Shadowlands is that we are in a whole new reality where the perfect world exists for every mortal. I won&#8217;t go too far into my disappointment in the fact that not only do we only see 5 of these worlds, no other worlds are even mentioned. Why not have Torghast be a place to show us glimpses of all the other worlds that exist in the Shadowlands? Each floor could be a new world, or perhaps just an illusion of a ravaged version of a world where the Mawsworn are torturing that world&#8217;s inhabitants. Shadowlands opens a whole new universe of lore, but we&#8217;re seeing such a small portion of it so far. Something needs to be starting to build up the lore of the other worlds that exist in the Shadowlands; why not use Torghast to do so?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Future of Torghast</h2>



<p>Torghast is full of potential. Unfortunately, it currently seems to be going the same way that Island Expeditions in BfA did: a required, boring grind. The conflict between just-for-fun and a challenging, rewarding endgame experience are at odds with each other. If Torghast is to survive, Blizz needs to pick just one.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background has-vivid-purple-background-color has-vivid-purple-color"/>



<script async="" src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-4537180102637521" crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:block; text-align:center;" data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-4537180102637521" data-ad-slot="5280630734"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-text-color has-background" style="background-color:#663399;color:#663399"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
